{
	"description": "Kanji for 日本漢字能力検定 4級",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "一人", "answers": [ "ひとり" ], "comment": "one person\nalone; unmarried; solitary" },
	{ "question": "一日", "answers": [ "ついたち", "いちにち", "いちじつ" ], "comment": "one day\nfirst day of the month\nfirst day of the month\nfirst ten days of the lunar month\nfirst day of the month\nfirst ten days of the lunar month" },
	{ "question": "七夕", "answers": [ "たなばた" ], "comment": "Star Festival (held in July or August); Tanabata; Festival of the Weaver" },
	{ "question": "万歳", "answers": [ "ばんざい" ], "comment": "door-to-door comedic duo\ncrying \"banzai\" (or raising one's hands in the banzai gesture)\nsomething worthy of celebration\ngiving up\nlong time\neternal life (and prosperity)\nbanzai (a celebratory cheer); hurrah (hooray, hurray)" },
	{ "question": "丈夫", "answers": [ "じょうぶ" ], "comment": "healthy; robust; strong; solid; durable\nhero; manly person; warrior" },
	{ "question": "三味線", "answers": [ "しゃみせん" ], "comment": "shamisen; samisen; three-stringed Japanese lute" },
	{ "question": "上手", "answers": [ "じょうず" ], "comment": "skill; skillful; dexterity\nflattery\nupper part\nupper stream; upper course of a river\nright side of the stage (audience's or camera's POV); stage left (actor's POV)\nskillful (only in comparisons); dexterity (only in comparisons)\nover-arm grip on opponent's belt" },
	{ "question": "上旬", "answers": [ "じょうじゅん" ], "comment": "first 10 days of month" },
	{ "question": "下手", "answers": [ "へた" ], "comment": "humble position; inferior\nunderarm grip on opponent's belt\nlower part; foot; lower direction\nleft part of the stage (audience's or camera's POV); stage right (actor's POV)\nunskillful; poor; awkward\nimprudent; untactful" },
	{ "question": "不振", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "dullness; depression; slump; stagnation" },
	{ "question": "与える", "answers": [ "あたえる" ], "comment": "to give (esp. to someone of lower status); to bestow; to grant; to confer; to present; to award\nto provide; to afford; to offer; to supply\nto assign\nto cause\nto pass (a variable to a function)" },
	{ "question": "丘", "answers": [ "おか" ], "comment": "hill; height; knoll; rising ground\nbonus points awarded to the winner at the end of a game\nmound; hill" },
	{ "question": "中継", "answers": [ "ちゅうけい" ], "comment": "relay; hook-up\nrelay broadcasting\njoining; joint; intermediation; relaying; intermediary; relay; agency; brokerage\nmid-relief pitcher; middle reliever" },
	{ "question": "丹念", "answers": [ "たんねん" ], "comment": "painstaking; careful; meticulous; scrupulous; detailed; elaborate" },
	{ "question": "丹精", "answers": [ "たんせい" ], "comment": "working earnestly; sincerity; diligence; effort; pains" },
	{ "question": "主翼", "answers": [ "しゅよく" ], "comment": "main wings (of an aeroplane, airplane)" },
	{ "question": "久しい", "answers": [ "ひさしい" ], "comment": "long; long-continued; old (story)" },
	{ "question": "乱れる", "answers": [ "みだれる" ], "comment": "to be disordered; to be disarranged; to be disarrayed; to be disheveled; to be dishevelled\nto be discomposed; to be upset; to get confused; to be disturbed\nto lapse into chaos (due to war, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "乾かす", "answers": [ "かわかす" ], "comment": "to dry (clothes, etc.); to desiccate" },
	{ "question": "乾く", "answers": [ "かわく" ], "comment": "to get dry" },
	{ "question": "乾杯", "answers": [ "かんぱい" ], "comment": "toast; drink (in celebration or in honor of something)\ndrinking one's glass dry\ncheers" },
	{ "question": "乾燥", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "dryness; aridity; insipidity; dehydration; desiccation" },
	{ "question": "事項", "answers": [ "じこう" ], "comment": "matter; item; facts" },
	{ "question": "二十日", "answers": [ "はつか" ], "comment": "twentieth day of the month\ntwenty days" },
	{ "question": "互恵", "answers": [ "ごけい" ], "comment": "reciprocity; mutual benefit" },
	{ "question": "互角", "answers": [ "ごかく" ], "comment": "equality; evenness; par; good match" },
	{ "question": "五月", "answers": [ "さつき" ], "comment": "May\nfifth month of the lunar calendar\nsatsuki azalea (Rhododendron indicum)" },
	{ "question": "五月雨", "answers": [ "さみだれ" ], "comment": "early-summer rain" },
	{ "question": "井戸", "answers": [ "いど" ], "comment": "water well" },
	{ "question": "交互", "answers": [ "こうご" ], "comment": "mutual; reciprocal; alternate" },
	{ "question": "人影", "answers": [ "ひとかげ" ], "comment": "figure of a person; figures of people\nshadow of a person" },
	{ "question": "今朝", "answers": [ "けさ", "こんちょう" ], "comment": "this morning" },
	{ "question": "介入", "answers": [ "かいにゅう" ], "comment": "intervention" },
	{ "question": "介抱", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "nursing; looking after" },
	{ "question": "介護", "answers": [ "かいご" ], "comment": "nursing; care; caregiving; caring" },
	{ "question": "仕業", "answers": [ "しわざ" ], "comment": "deed (esp. negative); act; action; one's doing" },
	{ "question": "代替", "answers": [ "だいたい", "だいがえ" ], "comment": "substitution; alternation\nalternative; substitute\ntaking over (e.g. store or family's headship)\nsubrogation; substitution of one person for another (usu. a creditor)" },
	{ "question": "仮名", "answers": [ "かな" ], "comment": "alias; pseudonym; pen name; nom de plume\nkana; Japanese syllabary (i.e. hiragana, katakana)" },
	{ "question": "仰ぐ", "answers": [ "あおぐ" ], "comment": "to look up (at)\nto look up (to); to respect; to revere\nto ask for; to seek\nto turn to someone; to depend on\nto gulp down; to quaff; to take (e.g. poison)" },
	{ "question": "仰天", "answers": [ "ぎょうてん" ], "comment": "being amazed; being horrified; being taken aback" },
	{ "question": "任せる", "answers": [ "まかせる" ], "comment": "to entrust (e.g. a task) to another; to leave to\nto passively leave to someone else's facilities\nto leave to take its natural course\nto continue (something) in a natural fashion (without particular aim)\nto rely fully on one's (full strength, great ability, long time taken) to get something done" },
	{ "question": "伺い", "answers": [ "うかがい" ], "comment": "call; visit\ninquiry; enquiry; question" },
	{ "question": "伺う", "answers": [ "うかがう" ], "comment": "to ask; to inquire; to hear; to be told\nto implore (a god for an oracle); to seek direction (from your superior)\nto visit\nto speak to (a large crowd at a theatre, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "低迷", "answers": [ "ていめい" ], "comment": "hanging low (over); hovering around (price level); low hanging (e.g. clouds); sluggish (e.g. economy); slump; recession" },
	{ "question": "体操", "answers": [ "たいそう" ], "comment": "gymnastics; physical exercises; calisthenics" },
	{ "question": "余る", "answers": [ "あまる" ], "comment": "to remain; to be left over; to be in excess; to be too many" },
	{ "question": "余暇", "answers": [ "よか" ], "comment": "leisure; leisure time; spare time" },
	{ "question": "作為", "answers": [ "さくい" ], "comment": "artificiality\nact; commission (of a crime)" },
	{ "question": "供える", "answers": [ "そなえる" ], "comment": "to offer; to sacrifice; to dedicate" },
	{ "question": "供給", "answers": [ "きょうきゅう" ], "comment": "supply; provision" },
	{ "question": "依存", "answers": [ "いぞん" ], "comment": "dependence; dependent; reliance" },
	{ "question": "依然", "answers": [ "いぜん" ], "comment": "still; as yet; as it has been" },
	{ "question": "依頼", "answers": [ "いらい" ], "comment": "request; commission; dispatch; despatch\ndependence; trust" },
	{ "question": "価値", "answers": [ "かち" ], "comment": "value; worth; merit" },
	{ "question": "侵入", "answers": [ "しんにゅう" ], "comment": "invasion; incursion; raid; aggression; intrusion; trespass; penetration" },
	{ "question": "侵攻", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "invasion" },
	{ "question": "俗悪", "answers": [ "ぞくあく" ], "comment": "worldliness; vulgarity; coarseness" },
	{ "question": "保つ", "answers": [ "たもつ" ], "comment": "to keep; to preserve; to hold; to retain; to maintain; to support; to sustain; to last; to endure; to keep well (food); to wear well; to be durable" },
	{ "question": "信仰", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "(religious) faith; belief; creed" },
	{ "question": "信頼", "answers": [ "しんらい" ], "comment": "reliance; trust; faith; confidence" },
	{ "question": "倒れる", "answers": [ "たおれる" ], "comment": "to fall; to collapse; to drop; to fall senseless\nto be forced to bed (by illness, etc.)\nto die\nto go bankrupt; to be ruined; to have a bad debt\nto be defeated (in a game)\nto fall (of governments, dictators, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "倒壊", "answers": [ "とうかい" ], "comment": "destruction; collapse; crumbling" },
	{ "question": "倒産", "answers": [ "とうさん" ], "comment": "(corporate) bankruptcy; insolvency; commercial failure; failed business" },
	{ "question": "候補", "answers": [ "こうほ" ], "comment": "candidate; contender; prospect; pick; choice; list\ncandidacy; candidature; nomination" },
	{ "question": "偉い", "answers": [ "えらい" ], "comment": "great; excellent; admirable; remarkable; distinguished; important; celebrated; famous; eminent\nawful; terrible" },
	{ "question": "偉大", "answers": [ "いだい" ], "comment": "greatness" },
	{ "question": "偉容", "answers": [ "いよう" ], "comment": "dignity; majestic appearance" },
	{ "question": "停泊", "answers": [ "ていはく" ], "comment": "anchorage; moorings" },
	{ "question": "傍観", "answers": [ "ぼうかん" ], "comment": "looking on; remaining a spectator" },
	{ "question": "備える", "answers": [ "そなえる" ], "comment": "to furnish; to provide for; to equip; to install\nto have ready; to prepare for\nto possess (all that is needed); to be endowed with; to be armed with\nto be born with; to have since birth" },
	{ "question": "備蓄", "answers": [ "びちく" ], "comment": "stockpile; reserves; storing; stocking up; laying in (supplies)" },
	{ "question": "傾倒", "answers": [ "けいとう" ], "comment": "admiration; adoration; concentration on; idolizing; idolising" },
	{ "question": "傾向", "answers": [ "けいこう" ], "comment": "tendency; trend; inclination" },
	{ "question": "傾斜", "answers": [ "けいしゃ" ], "comment": "inclination; slant; slope; bevel; list; dip; tilt; lean" },
	{ "question": "僧坊", "answers": [ "そうぼう" ], "comment": "priests' temple quarters" },
	{ "question": "僧門", "answers": [ "そうもん" ], "comment": "priesthood; Buddhism" },
	{ "question": "優しい", "answers": [ "やさしい" ], "comment": "tender; kind; gentle; graceful; affectionate; amiable" },
	{ "question": "優れる", "answers": [ "すぐれる" ], "comment": "to surpass; to outstrip; to excel" },
	{ "question": "優秀", "answers": [ "ゆうしゅう" ], "comment": "superiority; excellence" },
	{ "question": "優雅", "answers": [ "ゆうが" ], "comment": "elegance; grace; refinement" },
	{ "question": "兄さん", "answers": [ "にいさん" ], "comment": "older brother; elder brother\nbrother (as older-brother figure in friendly and or work relationship)\n(vocative) young man; buddy; fella; laddie" },
	{ "question": "光沢", "answers": [ "こうたく" ], "comment": "brilliance; polish; lustre; luster; glossy finish (of photographs)" },
	{ "question": "光輝", "answers": [ "こうき" ], "comment": "brightness; splendour; splendor" },
	{ "question": "光陰", "answers": [ "こういん" ], "comment": "time; Father Time" },
	{ "question": "全般", "answers": [ "ぜんぱん" ], "comment": "(the) whole; universal; wholly; general; as a whole" },
	{ "question": "兼ねる", "answers": [ "かねる" ], "comment": "to be unable to; to find difficult (unpleasant, awkward, painful) to do\nto serve two or more functions or roles simultaneously; to contain (or combine) two or more features\nto work in two or more jobs simultaneously (positions, etc.); to do alongside\nto hesitate to do something (out of consideration for others)\nto think of the future (as well as the present)" },
	{ "question": "兼任", "answers": [ "けんにん" ], "comment": "concurrent post\nto hold two posts concurrently" },
	{ "question": "兼務", "answers": [ "けんむ" ], "comment": "holding two posts concurrently" },
	{ "question": "内需", "answers": [ "ないじゅ" ], "comment": "domestic demand" },
	{ "question": "再び", "answers": [ "ふたたび" ], "comment": "again; once more; a second time" },
	{ "question": "冒険", "answers": [ "ぼうけん" ], "comment": "risk; venture; adventure" },
	{ "question": "処分", "answers": [ "しょぶん" ], "comment": "disposal; dealing (with a problem); disposition; measure; procedure\npunishment\nputting down (e.g. diseased animal)" },
	{ "question": "処置", "answers": [ "しょち" ], "comment": "measure; step; dealing with\nmedical treatment" },
	{ "question": "凶作", "answers": [ "きょうさく" ], "comment": "bad harvest; poor crop" },
	{ "question": "凶弾", "answers": [ "きょうだん" ], "comment": "assassin's bullet" },
	{ "question": "凶暴", "answers": [ "きょうぼう" ], "comment": "brutal; atrocious; ferocious" },
	{ "question": "出払う", "answers": [ "ではらう" ], "comment": "to be all out" },
	{ "question": "出陣", "answers": [ "しゅつじん" ], "comment": "departure for the front" },
	{ "question": "分離", "answers": [ "ぶんり" ], "comment": "separation; partition; detachment; segregation; isolation" },
	{ "question": "刈る", "answers": [ "かる" ], "comment": "to cut (hair); to mow (grass); to harvest; to clip; to shear; to reap; to trim; to prune" },
	{ "question": "初旬", "answers": [ "しょじゅん" ], "comment": "first 10 days of the month" },
	{ "question": "別途", "answers": [ "べっと" ], "comment": "separate; special; another\nseparately" },
	{ "question": "到底", "answers": [ "とうてい" ], "comment": "by no means; not at all; (cannot) possibly; utterly; absolutely" },
	{ "question": "到着", "answers": [ "とうちゃく" ], "comment": "arrival" },
	{ "question": "到達", "answers": [ "とうたつ" ], "comment": "reaching; attaining; arrival" },
	{ "question": "制御", "answers": [ "せいぎょ" ], "comment": "control; governing; checking; suppression; repression; restraint; mastery; management" },
	{ "question": "刺激", "answers": [ "しげき" ], "comment": "stimulus; impetus; incentive; encouragement; motivation; provocation; excitement; thrill" },
	{ "question": "刻む", "answers": [ "きざむ" ], "comment": "to mince; to cut fine; to chop up; to hash; to shred\nto carve; to engrave; to chisel; to notch\nto tick away (time); to beat out (e.g. rhythm); to record the passing moments\nto etch (into one's mind); to remember distinctly\nto have tattooed\nto torment" },
	{ "question": "前途", "answers": [ "ぜんと" ], "comment": "future prospects; outlook; the journey ahead" },
	{ "question": "剣豪", "answers": [ "けんごう" ], "comment": "master fencer" },
	{ "question": "創刊", "answers": [ "そうかん" ], "comment": "launching (e.g. newspaper); first issue" },
	{ "question": "劣悪", "answers": [ "れつあく" ], "comment": "inferiority; coarseness" },
	{ "question": "勇猛", "answers": [ "ゆうもう" ], "comment": "daring; bravery; valor; valour" },
	{ "question": "勢い", "answers": [ "いきおい" ], "comment": "force; vigor; vigour; energy; spirit; life\ninfluence; authority; power; might\nimpetus; momentum; course (of events)\nnaturally; necessarily" },
	{ "question": "勧める", "answers": [ "すすめる" ], "comment": "to recommend; to advise; to encourage; to offer (wine)" },
	{ "question": "勧告", "answers": [ "かんこく" ], "comment": "advice; counsel; remonstrance; recommendation" },
	{ "question": "包含", "answers": [ "ほうがん" ], "comment": "inclusion; comprehension; implication\nto include; to comprise; to contain; to implicate" },
	{ "question": "北緯", "answers": [ "ほくい" ], "comment": "north latitude" },
	{ "question": "匹敵", "answers": [ "ひってき" ], "comment": "to be a match for; to rival; to equal; to compare with; to be equivalent to" },
	{ "question": "医療", "answers": [ "いりょう" ], "comment": "medical care; medical treatment" },
	{ "question": "単純", "answers": [ "たんじゅん" ], "comment": "simplicity; simple; uncomplicated" },
	{ "question": "博士", "answers": [ "はかせ" ], "comment": "doctorate; PhD; Dr (as a title)\nexpert; learned person" },
	{ "question": "占拠", "answers": [ "せんきょ" ], "comment": "occupation (e.g. of territory); exclusive possession" },
	{ "question": "危ない", "answers": [ "あぶない" ], "comment": "dangerous; risky; hazardous; perilous; precarious\nin danger; in jeopardy; critical; grave; at risk\nuncertain; unreliable; insecure; unsteady; doubtful\nclose (i.e. a close call); narrow\nlook out!; watch out!" },
	{ "question": "即答", "answers": [ "そくとう" ], "comment": "immediate reply" },
	{ "question": "厚い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "thick; deep; heavy\nkind; cordial; hospitable; warm; faithful\nabundant" },
	{ "question": "原稿", "answers": [ "げんこう" ], "comment": "manuscript; copy" },
	{ "question": "厳か", "answers": [ "おごそか" ], "comment": "solemn (ceremony, atmosphere, etc.); austere; grave; majestic; dignified; stately; impressive" },
	{ "question": "及ぶ", "answers": [ "およぶ" ], "comment": "to reach; to amount to; to befall; to happen to; to extend\nto be up to the task; to come up to\nto compare with; to be a match (for)\nto commit (a crime)\nto require (to do) (usu. used in the negative)" },
	{ "question": "友達", "answers": [ "ともだち" ], "comment": "friend; companion" },
	{ "question": "反響", "answers": [ "はんきょう" ], "comment": "echo; reverberation\nrepercussion; reaction; response; influence" },
	{ "question": "収める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to dedicate; to make an offering; to pay (fees)\nto supply\nto store\nto finish; to bring to a close\nto restore (something to its place)\nto achieve (e.g. a result)" },
	{ "question": "収納", "answers": [ "しゅうのう" ], "comment": "storage; putting or stowing away\nreceipt (of funds, payment, etc.)\nharvesting" },
	{ "question": "叫ぶ", "answers": [ "さけぶ" ], "comment": "to shout; to cry; to scream; to shriek; to yell; to exclaim\nto clamor (for or against); to clamour (for or against)" },
	{ "question": "召し", "answers": [ "めし" ], "comment": "summons; call" },
	{ "question": "召致", "answers": [ "しょうち" ], "comment": "calling together" },
	{ "question": "同姓", "answers": [ "どうせい" ], "comment": "same surname" },
	{ "question": "同姓同名", "answers": [ "どうせいどうめい" ], "comment": "(having) same family and personal name" },
	{ "question": "同盟", "answers": [ "どうめい" ], "comment": "alliance; union; league" },
	{ "question": "名刺", "answers": [ "めいし" ], "comment": "business card" },
	{ "question": "名残り", "answers": [ "なごり" ], "comment": "remains; traces; vestiges; relics\n(the sorrow of) parting\nend" },
	{ "question": "名称", "answers": [ "めいしょう" ], "comment": "name; title" },
	{ "question": "吐く", "answers": [ "はく", "（つく）" ], "comment": "to breathe out; to breathe\nto tell (a lie); to use (foul language)\nto vomit; to throw up; to spit up\nto vomit; to throw up; to spit up\nto emit; to send forth; to breathe out\nto give (an opinion); to make (a comment); to express; to tell\nto confess" },
	{ "question": "吐息", "answers": [ "といき" ], "comment": "sigh; long breath" },
	{ "question": "吐露", "answers": [ "とろ" ], "comment": "expressing one's mind; speaking out" },
	{ "question": "含蓄", "answers": [ "がんちく" ], "comment": "implication; significance; connotation; depth of meaning; complications of a problem" },
	{ "question": "吹く", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "to blow (e.g. wind); to play a wind instrument\nto emit; to spout\nto whistle\nto laugh; to burst into laughter\nto smelt; to mint\nto brag; to talk big" },
	{ "question": "咲く", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "to bloom" },
	{ "question": "唐突", "answers": [ "とうとつ" ], "comment": "abrupt; sudden" },
	{ "question": "営む", "answers": [ "いとなむ" ], "comment": "to run (a business); to operate; to conduct; to practice (law, medicine, etc.)\nto carry out; to perform; to lead (a life)\nto hold (a Buddhist or Shinto ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "嘆かわしい", "answers": [ "なげかわしい" ], "comment": "sad; wretched; deplorable" },
	{ "question": "嘆息", "answers": [ "たんそく" ], "comment": "sigh; grief; lamentation; deploring" },
	{ "question": "噴出", "answers": [ "ふんしゅつ" ], "comment": "spewing; gushing; spouting; eruption; effusion" },
	{ "question": "回避", "answers": [ "かいひ" ], "comment": "evasion; avoidance" },
	{ "question": "困る", "answers": [ "こまる" ], "comment": "to be troubled; to be worried; to be bothered; to be embarrassed; to be stumped" },
	{ "question": "圏内", "answers": [ "けんない" ], "comment": "(being) within range (radio, commuting, etc.); (being) within the sphere (e.g. of influence)" },
	{ "question": "土産", "answers": [ "みやげ" ], "comment": "present; souvenir\nproduct of the land\npresent; souvenir" },
	{ "question": "地盤", "answers": [ "じばん" ], "comment": "ground; crust (earth); bed (gravel, river, etc.)\nfoundation (building, etc.); base\nconstituency; power base; support (electoral); footing; foothold" },
	{ "question": "垂らす", "answers": [ "たらす" ], "comment": "to dribble; to spill\nto suspend; to hang down; to slouch; to dangle" },
	{ "question": "執る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to take (trouble); to attend (to business); to command (army)" },
	{ "question": "基づく", "answers": [ "もとづく" ], "comment": "to be grounded on; to be based on; to be due to; to originate from" },
	{ "question": "基盤", "answers": [ "きばん" ], "comment": "foundation; basis; base; footing; infrastructure\nbedrock\nsubstrate (circuit board)" },
	{ "question": "堅固", "answers": [ "けんご" ], "comment": "solid; strong; firm" },
	{ "question": "堅実", "answers": [ "けんじつ" ], "comment": "steady; sound; reliable; solid" },
	{ "question": "堤", "answers": [ "つつみ" ], "comment": "bank; embankment; dike" },
	{ "question": "増える", "answers": [ "ふえる" ], "comment": "to increase; to multiply" },
	{ "question": "壁画", "answers": [ "へきが" ], "comment": "fresco; mural; wall painting" },
	{ "question": "壊れる", "answers": [ "こわれる" ], "comment": "to be broken; to break\nto fall through; to come to nothing" },
	{ "question": "声援", "answers": [ "せいえん" ], "comment": "encouragement; cheering; support" },
	{ "question": "外泊", "answers": [ "がいはく" ], "comment": "spending night somewhere else (usu. away from home); sleepover; sleep over" },
	{ "question": "多忙", "answers": [ "たぼう" ], "comment": "busy; pressure of work" },
	{ "question": "大丈夫", "answers": [ "だいじょうぶ" ], "comment": "safe; all right; alright; OK; okay; sure\ncertainly; surely; undoubtedly\ngreat man; fine figure of a man\ngreat man; fine figure of a man" },
	{ "question": "大人", "answers": [ "おとな" ], "comment": "adult\nman of substance or virtue; gentleman\ngiant\nadult" },
	{ "question": "大抵", "answers": [ "たいてい" ], "comment": "mostly; ordinarily; usually; generally\nprobably\nmost; almost all\nordinary\nproper; appropriate; moderate" },
	{ "question": "天井", "answers": [ "てんじょう" ], "comment": "ceiling; ceiling price" },
	{ "question": "天賦", "answers": [ "てんぷ" ], "comment": "natural (e.g. talent); innate; inherent" },
	{ "question": "太刀", "answers": [ "たち" ], "comment": "long sword" },
	{ "question": "太鼓", "answers": [ "たいこ" ], "comment": "drum" },
	{ "question": "夫婦", "answers": [ "ふうふ" ], "comment": "married couple; spouses; husband and wife; couple; pair\nhis and hers; pair of objects, one larger (for man), one smaller (for woman)" },
	{ "question": "失脚", "answers": [ "しっきゃく" ], "comment": "losing one's standing; being overthrown; falling" },
	{ "question": "奇妙", "answers": [ "きみょう" ], "comment": "strange; queer; curious" },
	{ "question": "奇抜", "answers": [ "きばつ" ], "comment": "novel; original; striking; strange; eccentric; fantastic" },
	{ "question": "奇術", "answers": [ "きじゅつ" ], "comment": "magic; conjuring; sleight of hand; legerdemain" },
	{ "question": "奏でる", "answers": [ "かなでる" ], "comment": "to play an instrument (esp. string instruments)\nto dance" },
	{ "question": "奥", "answers": [ "おく" ], "comment": "inner part; inside; interior; depths (e.g. of a forest); back (of a house, drawer, etc.); bottom (e.g. of one's heart); recesses; heart" },
	{ "question": "奥歯", "answers": [ "おくば" ], "comment": "molars; back teeth" },
	{ "question": "奴隷", "answers": [ "どれい" ], "comment": "slave; servant\nslavery" },
	{ "question": "威儀", "answers": [ "いぎ" ], "comment": "dignity; majesty; dignified manner" },
	{ "question": "娘", "answers": [ "むすめ" ], "comment": "unmarried woman\nMiss\n-ess; -ette\n(my) daughter\ngirl (i.e. a young, unmarried woman)" },
	{ "question": "婚礼", "answers": [ "こんれい" ], "comment": "marriage ceremony; wedding" },
	{ "question": "婚約", "answers": [ "こんやく" ], "comment": "engagement; betrothal" },
	{ "question": "宅配", "answers": [ "たくはい" ], "comment": "home delivery" },
	{ "question": "宇宙", "answers": [ "うちゅう" ], "comment": "universe; cosmos; space" },
	{ "question": "実況", "answers": [ "じっきょう" ], "comment": "actual state (of things); real state; actual condition; real condition; actual scene\nlive; on-the-scene\nreporting live; live coverage; live broadcasting" },
	{ "question": "実績", "answers": [ "じっせき" ], "comment": "achievements; actual results; accomplishments; past results; track record" },
	{ "question": "宮殿", "answers": [ "きゅうでん" ], "comment": "palace" },
	{ "question": "寂しい", "answers": [ "さびしい" ], "comment": "lonely; lonesome; solitary; desolate" },
	{ "question": "寄せる", "answers": [ "よせる" ], "comment": "to come near; to let someone approach\nto bring near; to bring together; to collect; to gather\nto deliver (opinion, news, etc.); to send (e.g. a letter); to contribute; to donate\nto let someone drop by\nto add (numbers)\nto have feelings for (love, goodwill, trust, etc.)\nto rely upon for a time; to depend on\nto use as a pretext\nto put aside\nto press; to push; to force\nto include; to welcome (in a group); to let in" },
	{ "question": "密接", "answers": [ "みっせつ" ], "comment": "related; connected; close; intimate" },
	{ "question": "寝具", "answers": [ "しんぐ" ], "comment": "bedding" },
	{ "question": "寝食", "answers": [ "しんしょく" ], "comment": "bed and food; eating and sleeping" },
	{ "question": "寸劇", "answers": [ "すんげき" ], "comment": "short play; skit" },
	{ "question": "寸暇", "answers": [ "すんか" ], "comment": "moment's leisure; free minute" },
	{ "question": "対抗", "answers": [ "たいこう" ], "comment": "opposition; antagonism" },
	{ "question": "対称", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "symmetry\nsecond person" },
	{ "question": "専攻", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "major subject; special study" },
	{ "question": "尊厳", "answers": [ "そんげん" ], "comment": "dignity; majesty; sanctity" },
	{ "question": "尋常", "answers": [ "じんじょう" ], "comment": "common; usual" },
	{ "question": "導く", "answers": [ "みちびく" ], "comment": "to guide; to lead; to show the way; to conduct\nto derive; to deduce" },
	{ "question": "小豆", "answers": [ "あずき" ], "comment": "adzuki bean (Vigna angularis)" },
	{ "question": "就任", "answers": [ "しゅうにん" ], "comment": "inauguration; assumption of office" },
	{ "question": "就寝", "answers": [ "しゅうしん" ], "comment": "going to bed; retiring (for the night)" },
	{ "question": "尽力", "answers": [ "じんりょく" ], "comment": "efforts; exertion; endeavour; assistance; services" },
	{ "question": "尾翼", "answers": [ "びよく" ], "comment": "empennage; tail; tail assembly" },
	{ "question": "屈指", "answers": [ "くっし" ], "comment": "leading; foremost; preeminent; outstanding; one of the best" },
	{ "question": "届く", "answers": [ "とどく" ], "comment": "to reach; to arrive; to get through; to get at\nto be attentive; to pay attention\nto be delivered; to carry (e.g. sound)" },
	{ "question": "峠", "answers": [ "とうげ" ], "comment": "ridge; (mountain) pass; difficult part" },
	{ "question": "峰", "answers": [ "みね" ], "comment": "peak; summit; ridge; top\nback of a blade" },
	{ "question": "川原", "answers": [ "かわら" ], "comment": "dry river bed; river beach" },
	{ "question": "巡回", "answers": [ "じゅんかい" ], "comment": "going around; patrol; round; tour" },
	{ "question": "巡礼", "answers": [ "じゅんれい" ], "comment": "pilgrimage; pilgrim" },
	{ "question": "巨万", "answers": [ "きょまん" ], "comment": "huge fortune; millions" },
	{ "question": "巨漢", "answers": [ "きょかん" ], "comment": "giant" },
	{ "question": "差し", "answers": [ "さし" ], "comment": "between (e.g. two people); face to face\nhindrance; impediment\narrhythmic section of recitative in noh music\nprefix used for stress or emphasis\ncounter for traditional dance songs\nruler; measure" },
	{ "question": "市販", "answers": [ "しはん" ], "comment": "selling on the market (in the marketplace, in stores, etc.); making something commercially available\ncommercial (e.g. software); over-the-counter; off-the-shelf; store-bought" },
	{ "question": "希薄", "answers": [ "きはく" ], "comment": "thin (e.g. air); diluted; sparse; lean; weak; rarified; rarefied\nlacking (e.g. empathy); deficient; insufficient (e.g. zeal)" },
	{ "question": "帽子", "answers": [ "ぼうし" ], "comment": "hat; cap" },
	{ "question": "幅員", "answers": [ "ふくいん" ], "comment": "breadth, extent" },
	{ "question": "幼い", "answers": [ "おさない" ], "comment": "very young\nchildish; immature" },
	{ "question": "幾つ", "answers": [ "いくつ" ], "comment": "how many?\nhow old?" },
	{ "question": "幾分", "answers": [ "いくぶん" ], "comment": "somewhat; to some extent; to some degree\nsome; part; portion" },
	{ "question": "座る", "answers": [ "すわる" ], "comment": "to sit; to squat\nto assume (a position)\nto hold steady; to hold still" },
	{ "question": "延期", "answers": [ "えんき" ], "comment": "postponement; adjournment" },
	{ "question": "弾む", "answers": [ "はずむ" ], "comment": "to spring; to bound; to bounce; to be stimulated; to be encouraged; to get lively; to treat oneself to; to splurge on" },
	{ "question": "弾力", "answers": [ "だんりょく" ], "comment": "elasticity; flexibility" },
	{ "question": "弾圧", "answers": [ "だんあつ" ], "comment": "oppression; suppression; pressure" },
	{ "question": "彩る", "answers": [ "いろどる" ], "comment": "to colour; to color; to paint\nto apply make-up\nto decorate; to garnish; to adorn; to add flair" },
	{ "question": "影響", "answers": [ "えいきょう" ], "comment": "influence; effect\nto influence; to affect; to have an influence on; to impact; to have an effect on" },
	{ "question": "彼岸", "answers": [ "ひがん" ], "comment": "equinoctial week (when Buddhist services are held)\nBuddhist services during the equinoctial week\nnirvana" },
	{ "question": "征服", "answers": [ "せいふく" ], "comment": "conquest; subjugation; overcoming" },
	{ "question": "後輩", "answers": [ "こうはい" ], "comment": "junior (at work, school, etc.); younger people; younger student" },
	{ "question": "従う", "answers": [ "したがう" ], "comment": "to abide (by the rules); to obey; to follow; to accompany" },
	{ "question": "御殿", "answers": [ "ごてん" ], "comment": "palace; court" },
	{ "question": "微妙", "answers": [ "びみょう" ], "comment": "delicate; subtle; sensitive\ndifficult; delicate (situation); complicated\ndoubtful; questionable; dicey; tricky\nunspeakably wonderful; sublime; exquisite; marvelous" },
	{ "question": "徴収", "answers": [ "ちょうしゅう" ], "comment": "collection (of fees, taxes, etc.); levy" },
	{ "question": "心地", "answers": [ "ここち" ], "comment": "feeling; sensation; mood\nsensation of doing (usu. after -masu stem of verb)\npadding; lining; foundation" },
	{ "question": "志す", "answers": [ "こころざす" ], "comment": "to plan; to intend; to aspire to; to set aims (sights on)" },
	{ "question": "忘れる", "answers": [ "わすれる" ], "comment": "to forget; to leave carelessly; to be forgetful of; to forget about; to forget (an article)" },
	{ "question": "応援", "answers": [ "おうえん" ], "comment": "aid; assistance; help; reinforcement; rooting; barracking; support; cheering" },
	{ "question": "快い", "answers": [ "こころよい" ], "comment": "pleasant; agreeable" },
	{ "question": "怒り", "answers": [ "いかり" ], "comment": "anger; rage; fury; wrath; indignation" },
	{ "question": "怖い", "answers": [ "こわい" ], "comment": "scary; frightening; eerie; dreadful\n(I'm) afraid" },
	{ "question": "思慮", "answers": [ "しりょ" ], "comment": "prudence; discretion; thought" },
	{ "question": "急所", "answers": [ "きゅうしょ" ], "comment": "vitals; tender spot\nkey (of a problem); crux; essential point; secret\nmale crotch (as a target in fighting)\nvital point (critical place to make a move in the game of Go)" },
	{ "question": "恋心", "answers": [ "こいごころ" ], "comment": "one's love; awakening of love" },
	{ "question": "恐ろしい", "answers": [ "おそろしい" ], "comment": "terrible; dreadful; terrifying; frightening; frightened\nsurprising; startling; tremendous; amazing" },
	{ "question": "恐怖", "answers": [ "きょうふ" ], "comment": "fear; dread; dismay; terror; horror; scare; panic" },
	{ "question": "恒久", "answers": [ "こうきゅう" ], "comment": "permanent; perpetuity" },
	{ "question": "恒常", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "constancy" },
	{ "question": "恥じる", "answers": [ "はじる" ], "comment": "to feel ashamed" },
	{ "question": "恥ずかしい", "answers": [ "はずかしい" ], "comment": "shy; ashamed; embarrassed\ndisgraceful; shameful" },
	{ "question": "恥部", "answers": [ "ちぶ" ], "comment": "private parts; privates; genitalia; secret place" },
	{ "question": "恩恵", "answers": [ "おんけい" ], "comment": "grace; favor; favour; blessing; benefit" },
	{ "question": "息子", "answers": [ "むすこ" ], "comment": "son\npenis" },
	{ "question": "恵む", "answers": [ "めぐむ" ], "comment": "to bless; to show mercy to\nto give (money, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "悩む", "answers": [ "なやむ" ], "comment": "to be worried; to be troubled" },
	{ "question": "情けない", "answers": [ "なさけない" ], "comment": "miserable; pitiable; shameful; deplorable; pathetic" },
	{ "question": "情趣", "answers": [ "じょうしゅ" ], "comment": "mood; sentiment; artistic effect" },
	{ "question": "惨事", "answers": [ "さんじ" ], "comment": "disaster; tragedy; tragic incident; horrible accident" },
	{ "question": "惨状", "answers": [ "さんじょう" ], "comment": "disastrous scene; terrible spectacle" },
	{ "question": "感涙", "answers": [ "かんるい" ], "comment": "tears of gratitude" },
	{ "question": "慎重", "answers": [ "しんちょう" ], "comment": "careful; cautious; prudent; discreet; deliberate" },
	{ "question": "慢性", "answers": [ "まんせい" ], "comment": "chronicity; chronic" },
	{ "question": "戒め", "answers": [ "いましめ" ], "comment": "caution; admonition; warning; lesson\nprohibition; ban; commandment; precept\npunishment\ncaution; guard" },
	{ "question": "戒める", "answers": [ "いましめる" ], "comment": "to warn against; to caution against\nto admonish; to scold; to rebuke\nto prohibit; to forbid; to ban\nto be cautious\nto detest; to loathe\nto punish" },
	{ "question": "戯れる", "answers": [ "たわむれる" ], "comment": "to be playful; to gambol; to be amused (with something); to play; to sport; to frolic; to joke\nto flirt with" },
	{ "question": "戯曲", "answers": [ "ぎきょく" ], "comment": "play; drama" },
	{ "question": "戸惑う", "answers": [ "とまどう" ], "comment": "to be bewildered; to be perplexed" },
	{ "question": "扇形", "answers": [ "おうぎがた" ], "comment": "fan shape" },
	{ "question": "手伝う", "answers": [ "てつだう" ], "comment": "to help; to assist; to aid\nto contribute to; to be a factor in" },
	{ "question": "手柄", "answers": [ "てがら" ], "comment": "achievement; feat; meritorious deed; distinguished service" },
	{ "question": "払う", "answers": [ "はらう" ], "comment": "to pay (e.g. money, bill)\nto brush off; to wipe away; to clear away; to dust off; to cut off (e.g. branches)\nto drive away (e.g. one's competitors)\nto sell off (something unneeded); to dispose of\nto pay (e.g. attention); to show (e.g. respect, concern)\nto make (e.g. effort, sacrifice); to expend; to exert\nto move out (of one's own place); to vacate\nto sweep (e.g. one's legs); to knock aside\nto make a sweeping stroke (in Japanese calligraphy)\nto reset (an abacus)" },
	{ "question": "扱い", "answers": [ "あつかい" ], "comment": "treatment; service" },
	{ "question": "扱う", "answers": [ "あつかう" ], "comment": "to deal with (a person); to treat; to handle; to take care of; to entertain\nto deal with (a problem); to handle; to manage\nto operate (e.g. a machine); to handle; to work\nto deal in; to sell\nto cover (a topic); to treat; to discuss; to take up\nto treat A as B\nto mediate (an argument)\nto be too much for one; to find unmanageable\nto gossip" },
	{ "question": "承る", "answers": [ "うけたまわる" ], "comment": "to hear; to be told; to know\nto receive (order); to undertake; to comply; to take (a reservation, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "投与", "answers": [ "とうよ" ], "comment": "prescribing medicine; administering (medicine)" },
	{ "question": "投影", "answers": [ "とうえい" ], "comment": "projection" },
	{ "question": "投稿", "answers": [ "とうこう" ], "comment": "contribution; submission; posting (e.g. to a newsgroup or mailing list)" },
	{ "question": "抜群", "answers": [ "ばつぐん" ], "comment": "preeminence; distinction; extraordinariness\noutstanding; excellent; exceptional; surpassing; extraordinary; distinguished" },
	{ "question": "抱える", "answers": [ "かかえる" ], "comment": "to hold or carry under or in the arms\nto have (esp. problems, debts, etc.)\nto employ; to engage; to hire" },
	{ "question": "抵抗", "answers": [ "ていこう" ], "comment": "resistance; opposition; standing up to\nreluctance; repulsion; repugnance\nresistance; drag; friction\nelectrical resistance\nresistor" },
	{ "question": "抵触", "answers": [ "ていしょく" ], "comment": "collision; conflict\nbeing contrary; being incompatible; being inconsistent; being contradictory\nbeing in violation (of a law, treaty, etc.); contravention" },
	{ "question": "押さえる", "answers": [ "おさえる" ], "comment": "to pin something down; to hold something down; to hold something back; to stop; to restrain; to curb\nto seize; to grasp; to arrest\nto gain control of something; to govern; to keep down (e.g. information); to suppress\nto catch happening; to determine (important points); to find (proof); to understand" },
	{ "question": "押す", "answers": [ "おす" ], "comment": "to push; to press\nto apply pressure from above; to press down\nto stamp (i.e. a passport); to apply a seal\nto affix (e.g. gold leaf)\nto press (someone for something); to urge; to compel; to influence\nto overwhelm; to overpower; to repress\nto push (events along); to advance (a plan)\nto do in spite of ...; to do even though ...; to force\nto make sure\nto be pressed for time\nto advance troops; to attack\n(of light) to be diffused across an entire surface" },
	{ "question": "担う", "answers": [ "になう" ], "comment": "to carry on shoulder; to shoulder (gun)\nto bear (burden, responsibility, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "担任", "answers": [ "たんにん" ], "comment": "in charge (of something)\nclass teacher; homeroom teacher; form teacher" },
	{ "question": "拍子", "answers": [ "ひょうし" ], "comment": "(musical) time; tempo; beat; rhythm\nthe moment; the instance; chance" },
	{ "question": "拍手", "answers": [ "はくしゅ" ], "comment": "clapping hands; applause\nclapping one's hands in prayer (at a shrine)" },
	{ "question": "拍車", "answers": [ "はくしゃ" ], "comment": "(riding) spur" },
	{ "question": "招く", "answers": [ "まねく" ], "comment": "to invite; to ask\nto beckon; to wave someone in; to gesture to\nto call in; to send for; to summon\nto bring on oneself; to cause; to incur; to lead to; to result in" },
	{ "question": "拠点", "answers": [ "きょてん" ], "comment": "position; location; base; point" },
	{ "question": "拡幅", "answers": [ "かくふく" ], "comment": "widening (of a road)\nto widen (esp. a road)" },
	{ "question": "指摘", "answers": [ "してき" ], "comment": "pointing out; identification" },
	{ "question": "振興", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "promotion; encouragement" },
	{ "question": "捕らえる", "answers": [ "とらえる" ], "comment": "to catch; to capture; to seize; to arrest; to grab; to catch hold of\nto grasp (e.g. meaning); to perceive; to capture (e.g. features)\nto captivate; to move (one's heart)" },
	{ "question": "捕獲", "answers": [ "ほかく" ], "comment": "capture; seizure" },
	{ "question": "捨てる", "answers": [ "すてる" ], "comment": "to throw away; to cast away; to dump; to discard\nto abandon; to desert; to leave\nto give up; to resign" },
	{ "question": "採掘", "answers": [ "さいくつ" ], "comment": "mining" },
	{ "question": "探す", "answers": [ "さがす" ], "comment": "to search (for something desired, needed); to look for\nto search (for something lost); to seek (a suspect in a crime)" },
	{ "question": "探査", "answers": [ "たんさ" ], "comment": "probe; inquiry; enquiry; investigation" },
	{ "question": "接触", "answers": [ "せっしょく" ], "comment": "touch; contact" },
	{ "question": "描写", "answers": [ "びょうしゃ" ], "comment": "depiction; description; portrayal" },
	{ "question": "握る", "answers": [ "にぎる" ], "comment": "to clasp; to grasp; to grip; to clutch\nto make (nigirizushi, rice ball, etc.); to form; to press into shape; to mold; to mould\nto seize (power, etc.); to take hold of" },
	{ "question": "握力", "answers": [ "あくりょく" ], "comment": "grip (of hand); grip strength" },
	{ "question": "握手", "answers": [ "あくしゅ" ], "comment": "handshake" },
	{ "question": "揺らぐ", "answers": [ "ゆらぐ" ], "comment": "to swing; to sway; to shake; to tremble\nto waver; to feel shaken; to become unstable" },
	{ "question": "損なう", "answers": [ "そこなう" ], "comment": "to harm; to hurt; to injure; to damage; to spoil; to mar\nto fail to ...; to miss one's opportunity to ..." },
	{ "question": "搬入", "answers": [ "はんにゅう" ], "comment": "taking in; bringing in (esp. heavy objects, artwork, furniture); carrying in" },
	{ "question": "操る", "answers": [ "あやつる" ], "comment": "to manipulate; to operate; to handle; to operate (e.g. a machine); to steer (a ship)\nto have a good command of (a language); to be fluent in\nto operate a puppet; to pull the strings of a puppet\nto mastermind; to pull the strings; to control from the shadows\nto play (a musical instrument)" },
	{ "question": "支える", "answers": [ "ささえる" ], "comment": "to support; to prop; to sustain; to underlay; to hold up\nto hold at bay; to stem; to check\nto stick; to get stuck; to get caught; to get jammed; to clog\nto be unavailable; to be busy; to be occupied; to be full\nto be piled up (e.g. of work)\nto halt (in one's speech); to stumble (over one's words); to stutter; to stammer\nto feel blocked (of one's chest or throat, due to grief, anxiety, illness, etc.); to feel pressure; to feel pain" },
	{ "question": "攻守", "answers": [ "こうしゅ" ], "comment": "offense and defense; offence and defence; batting and fielding" },
	{ "question": "攻防", "answers": [ "こうぼう" ], "comment": "offense and defense; offence and defence" },
	{ "question": "故障", "answers": [ "こしょう" ], "comment": "breakdown; failure; fault; accident; out of order\ndamage; hurt\nobjection; protest" },
	{ "question": "敏感", "answers": [ "びんかん" ], "comment": "sensitive; alert; aware; susceptible" },
	{ "question": "敏腕", "answers": [ "びんわん" ], "comment": "ability; capability; competence; skill" },
	{ "question": "敏速", "answers": [ "びんそく" ], "comment": "quickness; agility; activity" },
	{ "question": "敬う", "answers": [ "うやまう" ], "comment": "to show respect; to honour; to honor" },
	{ "question": "敷く", "answers": [ "しく" ], "comment": "to spread out; to lay out\nto take a position\nto impose widely (e.g. over a city)" },
	{ "question": "敷物", "answers": [ "しきもの" ], "comment": "carpet; rug; matting; carpeting\nmat, mattress, quilt etc. spread out on the floor (or ground) and used to sit or sleep on\nspread; (cloth) cover; coaster" },
	{ "question": "斜線", "answers": [ "しゃせん" ], "comment": "oblique line; forward slash" },
	{ "question": "斜陽", "answers": [ "しゃよう" ], "comment": "setting sun\ndeclining (e.g. industry)" },
	{ "question": "断る", "answers": [ "ことわる" ], "comment": "to refuse; to reject; to dismiss; to turn down; to decline\nto inform; to give notice; to tell in advance\nto ask leave; to excuse oneself (from)" },
	{ "question": "断層", "answers": [ "だんそう" ], "comment": "fault; dislocation\ngap; discrepancy" },
	{ "question": "新郎", "answers": [ "しんろう" ], "comment": "bridegroom" },
	{ "question": "新鮮", "answers": [ "しんせん" ], "comment": "fresh" },
	{ "question": "日和", "answers": [ "ひより" ], "comment": "weather; climatic conditions\nfine weather; clear day\nsituation; state of affairs\nsea conditions; good day for sailing\nideal weather (for some action, event, etc.); perfect day" },
	{ "question": "旧姓", "answers": [ "きゅうせい" ], "comment": "one's original family name; maiden name" },
	{ "question": "映る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "to be reflected; to harmonize with (harmonise); to come out (photo); to be projected; to be displayed (on a screen)" },
	{ "question": "映画", "answers": [ "えいが" ], "comment": "movie; film" },
	{ "question": "昨日", "answers": [ "きのう", "さくじつ" ], "comment": "yesterday" },
	{ "question": "昨晩", "answers": [ "さくばん" ], "comment": "last night" },
	{ "question": "是正", "answers": [ "ぜせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; redressing; rectifying" },
	{ "question": "是認", "answers": [ "ぜにん" ], "comment": "approval" },
	{ "question": "時計", "answers": [ "とけい" ], "comment": "watch; clock; timepiece" },
	{ "question": "時雨", "answers": [ "しぐれ" ], "comment": "rain shower in late autumn (fall) or early winter\nseasonable rain" },
	{ "question": "普及", "answers": [ "ふきゅう" ], "comment": "diffusion; spread; popularization; promulgation; familiarization" },
	{ "question": "普通", "answers": [ "ふつう" ], "comment": "general; ordinary; usual\nnormally; generally; usually\nlocal train; train that stops at every station" },
	{ "question": "景色", "answers": [ "けしき" ], "comment": "scenery; scene; landscape" },
	{ "question": "暇", "answers": [ "ひま" ], "comment": "spare time; free time; leisure\ntime (e.g. time it takes to do something)\ntime off; day off; vacation; holiday; leave\nquitting (one's job); firing someone; divorcing (one's spouse)\n(of one's time) free; (of one's business) slow\nleaving; departing" },
	{ "question": "暖まる", "answers": [ "あたたまる" ], "comment": "to warm oneself; to sun oneself; to warm up; to get warm" },
	{ "question": "暗鬼", "answers": [ "あんき" ] },
	{ "question": "暦", "answers": [ "こよみ", "れき" ], "comment": "calendar; almanac" },
	{ "question": "暮れる", "answers": [ "くれる" ], "comment": "to get dark\nto end; to come to an end; to close; to run out\nto be sunk (e.g. in despair); to be lost" },
	{ "question": "曇る", "answers": [ "くもる" ], "comment": "to get cloudy; to cloud over; to become overcast\nto cloud up; to fog up; to mist up; to become dim\nto be gloomy; to be clouded (expression); to be downcast\nto look slightly downward (of a noh mask; indicating sadness, grief, etc.)\nto mumble; to mutter" },
	{ "question": "曇天", "answers": [ "どんてん" ], "comment": "dull (cloudy) weather" },
	{ "question": "更新", "answers": [ "こうしん" ], "comment": "renewal; update; innovation; improvement" },
	{ "question": "服飾", "answers": [ "ふくしょく" ], "comment": "clothing and accessories; attire" },
	{ "question": "朗らか", "answers": [ "ほがらか" ], "comment": "bright; cheerful; melodious" },
	{ "question": "木陰", "answers": [ "こかげ" ], "comment": "shade of tree; bower" },
	{ "question": "未詳", "answers": [ "みしょう" ], "comment": "unknown; unidentified" },
	{ "question": "本腰", "answers": [ "ほんごし" ], "comment": "strenuous effort; earnestness; seriousness" },
	{ "question": "朱肉", "answers": [ "しゅにく" ], "comment": "thick red ink (used for signature seals); red ink pad; vermillion ink; cinnabar ink" },
	{ "question": "机", "answers": [ "つくえ" ], "comment": "desk" },
	{ "question": "朽ちる", "answers": [ "くちる" ], "comment": "to rot; to decay\nto die in obscurity\nto be forgotten with time (often in neg.)" },
	{ "question": "果物", "answers": [ "くだもの" ], "comment": "fruit" },
	{ "question": "枯死", "answers": [ "こし" ], "comment": "withering; dying" },
	{ "question": "染まる", "answers": [ "そまる" ], "comment": "to be dyed\nto be tainted; to be infected; to be stained; to be steeped" },
	{ "question": "柔和", "answers": [ "にゅうわ" ], "comment": "gentle; mild; meek; tender" },
	{ "question": "柔弱", "answers": [ "にゅうじゃく" ], "comment": "weakness; effeminacy; enervation" },
	{ "question": "柔道", "answers": [ "じゅうどう" ], "comment": "judo" },
	{ "question": "栄枯", "answers": [ "えいこ" ], "comment": "vicissitudes; ups and downs" },
	{ "question": "栄誉", "answers": [ "えいよ" ], "comment": "honour; honor" },
	{ "question": "株", "answers": [ "かぶ" ], "comment": "stock; share\nstump\nroot; rootstock\nstrain (of bacteria, etc.)\ntradeable rank; goodwill\none's forte\nstake; post; pile; picket\nstump\nstump\ncounter for trees\nstump\nstump\nuseless item" },
	{ "question": "根拠", "answers": [ "こんきょ" ], "comment": "basis; foundation" },
	{ "question": "桃源郷", "answers": [ "とうげんきょう" ], "comment": "Arcady; Eden; Shangri-la" },
	{ "question": "梅雨", "answers": [ "つゆ" ], "comment": "rainy season (in Japan from early June to mid-July)\nrain during the rainy season" },
	{ "question": "極端", "answers": [ "きょくたん" ], "comment": "extreme; extremity" },
	{ "question": "権限", "answers": [ "けんげん" ], "comment": "power; authority; jurisdiction" },
	{ "question": "樹立", "answers": [ "じゅりつ" ], "comment": "establish; create" },
	{ "question": "欄干", "answers": [ "らんかん" ], "comment": "guardrail; handrail; bannister; balustrade; parapet\n(a person) shining like the stars or moon; (a person) crying endlessly" },
	{ "question": "欲しい", "answers": [ "ほしい" ], "comment": "wanted; wished for; in need of; desired\nI want (you) to" },
	{ "question": "歌謡", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "song; ballad" },
	{ "question": "歓喜", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "delight; great joy" },
	{ "question": "歓声", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "cheer; shout of joy" },
	{ "question": "歳入", "answers": [ "さいにゅう" ], "comment": "annual revenue (government); annual income (government); budget receipts" },
	{ "question": "歳月", "answers": [ "さいげつ" ], "comment": "time; years" },
	{ "question": "殖える", "answers": [ "ふえる" ], "comment": "to increase; to multiply" },
	{ "question": "殺到", "answers": [ "さっとう" ], "comment": "rush; flood; deluge" },
	{ "question": "殿堂", "answers": [ "でんどう" ], "comment": "palace; hall; shrine; temple; sanctuary\nhall of fame" },
	{ "question": "比べる", "answers": [ "くらべる" ], "comment": "to compare; to make a comparison\nto compete; to vie" },
	{ "question": "比較", "answers": [ "ひかく" ], "comment": "comparison" },
	{ "question": "民俗", "answers": [ "みんぞく" ], "comment": "folk customs; folkways; ethnic customs" },
	{ "question": "民謡", "answers": [ "みんよう" ], "comment": "folk song; popular song" },
	{ "question": "気迫", "answers": [ "きはく" ], "comment": "spirit; soul; drive; vigor; vigour" },
	{ "question": "水滴", "answers": [ "すいてき" ], "comment": "drop of water\nvessel for replenishing inkstone water" },
	{ "question": "永い", "answers": [ "ながい" ], "comment": "long (time); lengthy" },
	{ "question": "求婚", "answers": [ "きゅうこん" ], "comment": "marriage proposal; courtship" },
	{ "question": "汗", "answers": [ "あせ" ], "comment": "sweat; perspiration\nmoisture; condensation\nkhan (medieval ruler of a Tatary tribe)" },
	{ "question": "汚濁", "answers": [ "おだく" ], "comment": "pollution; contamination; corruption; graft" },
	{ "question": "沈着", "answers": [ "ちんちゃく" ], "comment": "settling or depositing (at the bottom of something); deposition; pigmentation\ncomposure; calmness" },
	{ "question": "沈黙", "answers": [ "ちんもく" ], "comment": "silence; being silent; quiet; hush\nreticence; inaction" },
	{ "question": "沖", "answers": [ "おき" ], "comment": "open sea" },
	{ "question": "沖合", "answers": [ "おきあい" ], "comment": "coast; offing; offshore" },
	{ "question": "沢登り", "answers": [ "さわのぼり" ], "comment": "climbing a gorge" },
	{ "question": "油脂", "answers": [ "ゆし" ], "comment": "fat; fats and oils" },
	{ "question": "沼", "answers": [ "ぬま" ], "comment": "marsh; swamp; wetland; bog; pond" },
	{ "question": "波及", "answers": [ "はきゅう" ], "comment": "spread; extension; influence; aftereffect; ripple" },
	{ "question": "波紋", "answers": [ "はもん" ], "comment": "ripple; ring on the water\nrepercussions\nJapanese slit drum; instrument made of iron with slits on top; makes a rippling sound" },
	{ "question": "注釈", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃく" ], "comment": "notes; comment; remark; annotation" },
	{ "question": "洗う", "answers": [ "あらう" ], "comment": "to wash; to cleanse; to rinse\nto inquire into; investigate\nto purify (one's heart)\nto lave (e.g. shore); to wash over (e.g. deck); to sweep" },
	{ "question": "活況", "answers": [ "かっきょう" ], "comment": "activity; briskness; prosperity" },
	{ "question": "派遣", "answers": [ "はけん" ], "comment": "dispatch; despatch; deployment\ntemporary employee (esp. from an agency); temporary worker; agency temp" },
	{ "question": "浜辺", "answers": [ "はまべ" ], "comment": "beach; foreshore" },
	{ "question": "浮動票", "answers": [ "ふどうひょう" ], "comment": "swing vote" },
	{ "question": "浮沈", "answers": [ "ふちん" ], "comment": "floating and sinking; rise and fall; ebb and flow; ups and downs" },
	{ "question": "海原", "answers": [ "うなばら" ], "comment": "ocean; sea; the deep" },
	{ "question": "海浜", "answers": [ "かいひん" ], "comment": "seaside; beachside" },
	{ "question": "浸入", "answers": [ "しんにゅう" ], "comment": "infiltration (e.g. of water); flooding" },
	{ "question": "浸水", "answers": [ "しんすい" ], "comment": "inundation; submersion; flood" },
	{ "question": "涙", "answers": [ "なみだ" ], "comment": "tear; tears; lachrymal secretion\nsympathy" },
	{ "question": "淡白", "answers": [ "たんぱく" ], "comment": "light (color, colour, taste); simple; plain\nfrank; candid; ingenuous; indifferent" },
	{ "question": "添う", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "to meet (one's expectations, etc.); to satisfy; to comply with\nto accompany; to stay by one's side\nto marry; to wed\nto be added" },
	{ "question": "添える", "answers": [ "そえる" ], "comment": "to garnish; to accompany (as a card does a gift)\nto add to as support; to prop up\nto accompany (as an aid, guide, translator, etc.)\nto mimic; to imitate\nto draw something near to oneself; to approach nearby" },
	{ "question": "添付", "answers": [ "てんぷ" ], "comment": "attachment (e.g. email); appendix (e.g. of a report, document, etc); annex; appendage; annexure" },
	{ "question": "清水", "answers": [ "しみず", "きよみず" ], "comment": "spring water\nclear (pure) water" },
	{ "question": "清潔", "answers": [ "せいけつ" ], "comment": "clean; hygienic; sanitary\npure; virtuous; immaculate" },
	{ "question": "済ます", "answers": [ "すます" ], "comment": "to finish; to get it over with; to conclude\nto settle; to pay back\nto get along (without something); to make do with (without)" },
	{ "question": "減らす", "answers": [ "へらす" ], "comment": "to abate; to decrease; to diminish; to shorten" },
	{ "question": "減税", "answers": [ "げんぜい" ], "comment": "tax reduction" },
	{ "question": "渡航", "answers": [ "とこう" ], "comment": "voyage" },
	{ "question": "測距", "answers": [ "そくきょ" ], "comment": "distance surveying; ranging" },
	{ "question": "満杯", "answers": [ "まんぱい" ], "comment": "full" },
	{ "question": "溶接", "answers": [ "ようせつ" ], "comment": "weld; welding" },
	{ "question": "漫画", "answers": [ "まんが" ], "comment": "cartoon; comic; comic strip" },
	{ "question": "潔い", "answers": [ "いさぎよい" ], "comment": "manly; sportsmanlike; gracious; gallant; resolute; brave\npure (heart, actions, etc.); upright; blameless\nunsullied (e.g. scenery or object); pure; clean" },
	{ "question": "澄ます", "answers": [ "すます" ], "comment": "to clear; to make clear\nto be unruffled; to look unconcerned; to feign indifference\nto look demure; to look prim; to put on airs\nto strain (one's ears); to listen carefully" },
	{ "question": "澄んだ", "answers": [ "すんだ" ], "comment": "clear; serene; limpid; lucid; transparent; crystal; translucent; pellucid" },
	{ "question": "澄明", "answers": [ "ちょうめい" ], "comment": "clear and bright" },
	{ "question": "激しい", "answers": [ "はげしい" ], "comment": "violent; furious; tempestuous\nextreme; intense; fierce; strong\nfervent; vehement\nincessant; relentless\nprecipitous; steep" },
	{ "question": "激論", "answers": [ "げきろん" ], "comment": "heated discussion" },
	{ "question": "濁る", "answers": [ "にごる" ], "comment": "to become muddy; to become cloudy; to get impure (of a liquid, gas, etc.)\nto become dull (of a sound, color, etc.); to become hoarse\nto become impure (of a heart, society, etc.); to be corrupted; to be polluted\nto become voiced; to add voiced consonant marks" },
	{ "question": "濁流", "answers": [ "だくりゅう" ], "comment": "muddy stream" },
	{ "question": "濃密", "answers": [ "のうみつ" ], "comment": "thick; dense; rich (as in taste or content); deep (colour); strong (smell, scent)\ncrowded" },
	{ "question": "点呼", "answers": [ "てんこ" ], "comment": "roll-call; muster" },
	{ "question": "点滴", "answers": [ "てんてき" ], "comment": "raindrops; falling drop of water\nintravenous drip; IV; drip-feed" },
	{ "question": "為替", "answers": [ "かわせ" ], "comment": "money order; draft\nexchange (e.g. foreign)" },
	{ "question": "烈風", "answers": [ "れっぷう" ], "comment": "gale; violent (strong) wind" },
	{ "question": "無尽蔵", "answers": [ "むじんぞう" ], "comment": "inexhaustible supply" },
	{ "question": "焼却", "answers": [ "しょうきゃく" ], "comment": "incineration; destroy by fire" },
	{ "question": "煙突", "answers": [ "えんとつ" ], "comment": "chimney; smokestack; funnel (of a ship); stovepipe\ncarrying a passenger without turning on the taximeter" },
	{ "question": "煮豆", "answers": [ "にまめ" ], "comment": "cooked beans" },
	{ "question": "熟れる", "answers": [ "うれる" ], "comment": "to ripen (fruit, grain, etc.); to become ripe\nto be digested\nto master (a skill); to be proficient; to be accomplished; to be well developed\nto mature (e.g. personality); to mellow\nto mature (foodstuff); to be properly aged\nto mature (esp. by fermentation); to ripen (e.g. wine, cheese); to be properly aged; to become seasoned\nto rot" },
	{ "question": "熱狂", "answers": [ "ねっきょう" ], "comment": "wild enthusiasm; being crazy about" },
	{ "question": "熱狂的", "answers": [ "ねっきょうてき" ], "comment": "wildly enthusiastic; crazy (about something)" },
	{ "question": "燃える", "answers": [ "もえる" ], "comment": "to burn; to get fired up" },
	{ "question": "爆弾", "answers": [ "ばくだん" ], "comment": "bomb\nalcohol with liquor added (esp. wine-based shochu highball, also beer with whiskey)" },
	{ "question": "爆撃", "answers": [ "ばくげき" ], "comment": "bombing (raid)" },
	{ "question": "父さん", "answers": [ "とうさん" ], "comment": "father; dad; papa; pa; pop; daddy; dada" },
	{ "question": "牛乳", "answers": [ "ぎゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "(cow's) milk" },
	{ "question": "物騒", "answers": [ "ぶっそう" ], "comment": "dangerous; unsettled; troubled; disturbed; insecure" },
	{ "question": "犯す", "answers": [ "おかす" ], "comment": "to commit (e.g. crime); to perpetrate; to make (e.g. mistake)\nto break (e.g. rule); to violate; to transgress; to contravene\nto rape; to violate; to ravish; to deflower" },
	{ "question": "狂言", "answers": [ "きょうげん" ], "comment": "kyogen; farce presented between noh plays or during the interlude of a noh play\nkabuki play; kabuki performance\nmake-believe; ruse; trick" },
	{ "question": "狩り", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "hunting\nharvesting (e.g. berries, fruit); picking; gathering" },
	{ "question": "独り", "answers": [ "ひとり" ], "comment": "one person\nalone; unmarried; solitary" },
	{ "question": "独占", "answers": [ "どくせん" ], "comment": "monopoly; monopolization\nhogging; keeping to oneself" },
	{ "question": "狭い", "answers": [ "せまい" ], "comment": "narrow; confined; small" },
	{ "question": "猛威", "answers": [ "もうい" ], "comment": "fury; power; menace" },
	{ "question": "獣医", "answers": [ "じゅうい" ], "comment": "veterinarian" },
	{ "question": "獣道", "answers": [ "けものみち" ], "comment": "animal trail; game trail" },
	{ "question": "獲物", "answers": [ "えもの" ], "comment": "game; spoils; trophy; prey" },
	{ "question": "玄米", "answers": [ "げんまい" ], "comment": "unpolished rice; unmilled rice; brown rice\nunpolished rice; unmilled rice; brown rice\nblack rice" },
	{ "question": "玄関", "answers": [ "げんかん" ], "comment": "entranceway; entry hall; vestibule; foyer; entryway; mud room" },
	{ "question": "率いる", "answers": [ "ひきいる" ], "comment": "to lead; to spearhead (a group); to command (troops)" },
	{ "question": "珍しい", "answers": [ "めずらしい" ], "comment": "unusual; rare; curious\nnew; novel\nfine (e.g. gift)" },
	{ "question": "珍味", "answers": [ "ちんみ" ], "comment": "delicacy; dainties" },
	{ "question": "珍奇", "answers": [ "ちんき" ], "comment": "strange; rare; novel; curious" },
	{ "question": "珍獣", "answers": [ "ちんじゅう" ], "comment": "rare (or peculiar) animal" },
	{ "question": "現れる", "answers": [ "あらわれる" ], "comment": "to appear; to come in sight; to become visible; to come out; to embody; to materialize; to materialise\nto be expressed (e.g. emotions); to become apparent (e.g. trends, effects)" },
	{ "question": "環境", "answers": [ "かんきょう" ], "comment": "environment; circumstance" },
	{ "question": "甘い", "answers": [ "あまい" ], "comment": "sweet-tasting; sweet; sugary; sugared\nfragrant (smelling); sweet (music)\nlightly salted; light in salt; not spicy\nnaive; overly optimistic; soft on; generous; indulgent; easy-going; lenient\nhalf-hearted; not finished properly\ninsufficient; not satisfactory; inadequate; loose\nmild\ntempting; enticing; luring\nskillful; skilful; clever; expert; wise; successful\ndelicious; appetizing; appetising; tasty\nfortunate; splendid; promising" },
	{ "question": "甘美", "answers": [ "かんび" ], "comment": "sweet (e.g. fruit, melody, dream); luscious" },
	{ "question": "甘言", "answers": [ "かんげん" ], "comment": "sweet words; smooth talk; cajolery; flattery; sycophancy" },
	{ "question": "異なる", "answers": [ "ことなる" ], "comment": "to differ; to vary; to disagree" },
	{ "question": "異彩", "answers": [ "いさい" ], "comment": "conspicuousness (usu. color); prominence; distinctiveness" },
	{ "question": "畳", "answers": [ "たたみ" ], "comment": "counter for tatami mats\nmeasure of room size (in mat units)\ntatami mat; Japanese straw floor coverings\nfolding paper-case; kimono wrapping paper" },
	{ "question": "疲れる", "answers": [ "つかれる" ], "comment": "to get tired; to tire\nto be worn out (e.g. of well used objects)\nto starve" },
	{ "question": "疲労", "answers": [ "ひろう" ], "comment": "fatigue; weariness" },
	{ "question": "病床", "answers": [ "びょうしょう" ], "comment": "sickbed" },
	{ "question": "痛い", "answers": [ "いたい" ], "comment": "painful; sore\nexceeding" },
	{ "question": "痛める", "answers": [ "いためる" ], "comment": "to hurt; to injure; to cause pain\nto harm; to damage; to spoil\nto worry; to bother; to be grieved over; to afflict\nto cause financial loss; to hurt one's pocket\nto hurt; to ache" },
	{ "question": "痛快", "answers": [ "つうかい" ], "comment": "exhilarating; thrilling; intensely pleasurable" },
	{ "question": "発掘", "answers": [ "はっくつ" ], "comment": "excavation; exhumation\ndiscovery (e.g. new talent)" },
	{ "question": "発汗", "answers": [ "はっかん" ], "comment": "sweating; perspiration; sudation; hidrosis; diaphoresis" },
	{ "question": "白髪", "answers": [ "しらが", "はくはつ" ], "comment": "white hair; grey hair; gray hair" },
	{ "question": "皆勤", "answers": [ "かいきん" ], "comment": "perfect attendance" },
	{ "question": "皆無", "answers": [ "かいむ" ], "comment": "nonexistent; nil; none; nothing (at all); bugger-all" },
	{ "question": "皮膚", "answers": [ "ひふ" ], "comment": "skin" },
	{ "question": "盆地", "answers": [ "ぼんち" ], "comment": "basin (e.g. between mountains)" },
	{ "question": "盆景", "answers": [ "ぼんけい" ], "comment": "miniature garden; tray landscape" },
	{ "question": "盗む", "answers": [ "ぬすむ" ], "comment": "to steal" },
	{ "question": "盗掘", "answers": [ "とうくつ" ], "comment": "illegal digging; illegal mining; grave robbing; tomb robbing" },
	{ "question": "盗用", "answers": [ "とうよう" ], "comment": "embezzlement; fraudulent use; plagiarism" },
	{ "question": "盛る", "answers": [ "さかる" ], "comment": "to prosper; to flourish\nto copulate (animals)\nto serve (food, etc.); to dish out\nto fill up; to pile up; to heap\nto prescribe; to administer; to dose out\nto put into (e.g. information in a report)\nto mark out (e.g. scale); to graduate (e.g. thermometer)\nto exaggerate; to apply heavy makeup" },
	{ "question": "監査", "answers": [ "かんさ" ], "comment": "inspection; audit; judgement; judgment" },
	{ "question": "監禁", "answers": [ "かんきん" ], "comment": "confinement" },
	{ "question": "監視", "answers": [ "かんし" ], "comment": "monitoring; watching; observation; surveillance; guarding; inspection" },
	{ "question": "目撃", "answers": [ "もくげき" ], "comment": "witnessing; observing; sighting" },
	{ "question": "直訴", "answers": [ "じきそ" ], "comment": "direct appeal" },
	{ "question": "相互", "answers": [ "そうご" ], "comment": "mutual; reciprocal" },
	{ "question": "相違", "answers": [ "そうい" ], "comment": "difference; discrepancy; variation" },
	{ "question": "盾", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "shield; buckler; escutcheon; pretext" },
	{ "question": "真剣", "answers": [ "しんけん" ], "comment": "seriousness; earnestness\nreal sword (as opposed to unsharpened or wooden practice weapon)" },
	{ "question": "眠る", "answers": [ "ねむる" ], "comment": "to sleep (not necessarily lying down)\nto die\nto lie idle (e.g. of resources); to be dormant; to be unused\nto close one's eyes" },
	{ "question": "瞬く", "answers": [ "またたく", "まだたく", "まばたく", "めばたく", "しばたたく", "しばだたく", "しばたく" ], "comment": "to blink (one's eyes); to wink; to bat\nto twinkle (e.g. stars); to flicker; to waver" },
	{ "question": "瞬間", "answers": [ "しゅんかん" ], "comment": "moment; second; instant" },
	{ "question": "矛先", "answers": [ "ほこさき" ], "comment": "point of spear; spearhead\nbrunt; aim of attack; force of argument" },
	{ "question": "矛盾", "answers": [ "むじゅん" ], "comment": "contradiction; inconsistency" },
	{ "question": "砂丘", "answers": [ "さきゅう" ], "comment": "sand dune; sand hill" },
	{ "question": "砲丸", "answers": [ "ほうがん" ], "comment": "shell; shots; cannon ball" },
	{ "question": "破れる", "answers": [ "やぶれる" ], "comment": "to break; to be smashed\nto split; to crack; to fissure; to be torn\nto be divided; to cleave\nto come to light; to be identified; to be established; to become clear\nto get torn; to tear; to rip; to break; to wear out\nto be broken off (of negotiations, etc.); to break down; to collapse; to fall into ruin" },
	{ "question": "示す", "answers": [ "しめす" ], "comment": "to (take out and) show; to demonstrate; to tell; to exemplify; to make apparent\nto point out (finger, clock hand, needle, etc.)\nto indicate; to show; to represent; to signify; to display" },
	{ "question": "祈る", "answers": [ "いのる" ], "comment": "to pray; to wish" },
	{ "question": "祈願", "answers": [ "きがん" ], "comment": "prayer; supplication" },
	{ "question": "神妙", "answers": [ "しんみょう" ], "comment": "meek; quiet; docile; humble; faithful; obedient\nmysterious; marvelous; marvellous" },
	{ "question": "禁煙", "answers": [ "きんえん" ], "comment": "abstaining from smoking; quitting smoking\nNo Smoking!; Smoking Prohibited!" },
	{ "question": "秀麗", "answers": [ "しゅうれい" ], "comment": "graceful; beautiful" },
	{ "question": "秘める", "answers": [ "ひめる" ], "comment": "to hide; to keep to oneself" },
	{ "question": "称賛", "answers": [ "しょうさん" ], "comment": "praise; admiration; commendation; approbation" },
	{ "question": "稲刈り", "answers": [ "いねかり" ], "comment": "rice reaping; rice harvesting" },
	{ "question": "穀物", "answers": [ "こくもつ" ], "comment": "grain; cereal; corn" },
	{ "question": "穴", "answers": [ "あな" ], "comment": "hole\ndeficit; shortage; missing person (in a team, meeting, etc.)\nvacancy; opening\nflaw\nprofitable place (or item, etc.) not well known by others\nupset victory (with a large payoff)\npit (of a theater)\nhiding place\nunderbelly (of society, etc.)\nass; arse; buttocks\nrear; end\nacupuncture point\nhole; notch" },
	{ "question": "空欄", "answers": [ "くうらん" ], "comment": "blank space" },
	{ "question": "突堤", "answers": [ "とってい" ], "comment": "breakwater" },
	{ "question": "突拍子もない", "answers": [ "とっぴょうしもない" ], "comment": "astounding; tremendous; crazy; exorbitant" },
	{ "question": "端麗", "answers": [ "たんれい" ], "comment": "grace; beauty; elegance" },
	{ "question": "竹刀", "answers": [ "しない" ], "comment": "bamboo sword (for kendo); bamboo fencing stick" },
	{ "question": "筆致", "answers": [ "ひっち" ], "comment": "literary style; stroke of the brush; touch" },
	{ "question": "箇所", "answers": [ "かしょ" ], "comment": "passage; place; point; part" },
	{ "question": "箇条", "answers": [ "かじょう" ], "comment": "item; article; clause; section; point" },
	{ "question": "箇条書き", "answers": [ "かじょうがき" ], "comment": "itemized form; itemised form; itemization; itemisation" },
	{ "question": "箱詰め", "answers": [ "はこづめ" ], "comment": "packed in a box (e.g. chocolates)" },
	{ "question": "範囲", "answers": [ "はんい" ], "comment": "extent; scope; sphere; range; span" },
	{ "question": "米粒", "answers": [ "こめつぶ" ], "comment": "grain of rice" },
	{ "question": "精進", "answers": [ "しょうじん" ], "comment": "concentration; diligence; devotion\nasceticism; zeal in one's quest for enlightenment\nadherence to a vegetarian diet" },
	{ "question": "精鋭", "answers": [ "せいえい" ], "comment": "elite; best; pick; cream of the crop" },
	{ "question": "紋章", "answers": [ "もんしょう" ], "comment": "crest; coat of arms" },
	{ "question": "素足", "answers": [ "すあし" ], "comment": "bare feet" },
	{ "question": "紫", "answers": [ "むらさき" ], "comment": "purple; violet\nLithospermum erythrorhizon (species of gromwell)\ntype of soy sauce" },
	{ "question": "紫外線", "answers": [ "しがいせん" ], "comment": "ultra-violet rays" },
	{ "question": "紹介", "answers": [ "しょうかい" ], "comment": "introduction; presentation; referral; listing" },
	{ "question": "終盤", "answers": [ "しゅうばん" ], "comment": "endgame; final stage" },
	{ "question": "結婚", "answers": [ "けっこん" ], "comment": "marriage" },
	{ "question": "絶える", "answers": [ "たえる" ], "comment": "to die out; to peter out; to become extinct\nto cease; to be stopped; to be discontinued; to be cut off" },
	{ "question": "絶叫", "answers": [ "ぜっきょう" ], "comment": "scream; shriek; shout; exclamation" },
	{ "question": "絹", "answers": [ "きぬ" ], "comment": "silk" },
	{ "question": "継続", "answers": [ "けいぞく" ], "comment": "continuation" },
	{ "question": "維持", "answers": [ "いじ" ], "comment": "maintenance; preservation; improvement" },
	{ "question": "緯度", "answers": [ "いど" ], "comment": "latitude (nav.)" },
	{ "question": "縁談", "answers": [ "えんだん" ], "comment": "marriage proposal; marriage talks" },
	{ "question": "縁起", "answers": [ "えんぎ" ], "comment": "omen; sign of luck\norigin; causation" },
	{ "question": "縦", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "the vertical; height\nfront-to-back; length\nnorth-to-south\nvertical (relationship); hierarchy\n(weaving) warp\nselfish; self-indulgent; arbitrary\neven if" },
	{ "question": "縮む", "answers": [ "ちぢむ" ], "comment": "to shrink; to contract; to diminish (in size)" },
	{ "question": "繁忙", "answers": [ "はんぼう" ], "comment": "pressure of business; busy" },
	{ "question": "繁栄", "answers": [ "はんえい" ], "comment": "prospering; prosperity; thriving; flourishing" },
	{ "question": "繁茂", "answers": [ "はんも" ], "comment": "luxuriant growth; rankness (of weeds)" },
	{ "question": "繰り", "answers": [ "くり" ], "comment": "reeling; winding (thread)" },
	{ "question": "罰則", "answers": [ "ばっそく" ], "comment": "punishment; penalty\npenal regulations; penal code" },
	{ "question": "罰金", "answers": [ "ばっきん" ], "comment": "fine; penalty" },
	{ "question": "群れる", "answers": [ "むれる" ], "comment": "to crowd; to flock; to swarm" },
	{ "question": "老朽", "answers": [ "ろうきゅう" ], "comment": "superannuated; decrepitude" },
	{ "question": "老舗", "answers": [ "しにせ" ], "comment": "old shop; shop of long standing\nwell-established; first of the kind; veteran" },
	{ "question": "耐える", "answers": [ "たえる" ], "comment": "to bear; to stand; to endure; to put up with\nto support; to withstand; to resist; to brave\nto be fit for; to be equal to" },
	{ "question": "耐久", "answers": [ "たいきゅう" ], "comment": "endurance; persistence" },
	{ "question": "職業", "answers": [ "しょくぎょう" ], "comment": "occupation; business" },
	{ "question": "肥やす", "answers": [ "こやす" ], "comment": "to fertilize; to fertilise; to manure; to enrich" },
	{ "question": "肩", "answers": [ "かた" ], "comment": "shoulder" },
	{ "question": "肩車", "answers": [ "かたぐるま" ], "comment": "giving someone a ride on one's shoulders\nshoulder wheel (judo)" },
	{ "question": "背丈", "answers": [ "せたけ" ], "comment": "stature; height" },
	{ "question": "胴", "answers": [ "どう" ], "comment": "trunk; torso; body; abdomen; waist\nplastron (in kendo); touching the plastron (kimari-te in kendo)\nframe (of a drum, etc.); sound box (of a shamisen, etc.); hull (of a ship)" },
	{ "question": "胴衣", "answers": [ "どうい" ], "comment": "padded, sleeveless undergarment; vest\n(sleeveless) undergarment; padded undershirt" },
	{ "question": "脂汗", "answers": [ "あぶらあせ" ], "comment": "cold sweat; greasy sweat" },
	{ "question": "脂肪", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "fat; grease; blubber" },
	{ "question": "脈絡", "answers": [ "みゃくらく" ], "comment": "chain of reasoning; logical connection; coherence; context" },
	{ "question": "脚", "answers": [ "あし" ], "comment": "foot\nleg\ngait\npace\nbottom structural component (i.e. radical) of a kanji\nmoney; coin\ncounter for chairs or seats" },
	{ "question": "脱却", "answers": [ "だっきゃく" ], "comment": "ridding oneself; freeing oneself of; growing out of; overcoming; outgrowing" },
	{ "question": "脱帽", "answers": [ "だつぼう" ], "comment": "removing one's hat\nadmiring someone greatly; \"taking off one's hat\" to someone" },
	{ "question": "脱衣", "answers": [ "だつい" ], "comment": "undressing; taking off one's clothes" },
	{ "question": "脱退", "answers": [ "だったい" ], "comment": "secession; retirement; withdrawal (e.g. from a lawsuit)" },
	{ "question": "腐る", "answers": [ "くさる" ], "comment": "to rot; to go bad; to decay; to spoil; to fester; to decompose; to turn sour (e.g. milk)\nto corrode; to weather; to crumble\nto become useless; to blunt; to weaken (from lack of practice)\nto become depraved; to be degenerate; to be morally bankrupt; to be corrupt\nto be depressed; to be dispirited; to feel discouraged; to feel down\nindicates scorn or disdain for another's action\nto lose a bet\nto be drenched; to become sopping wet" },
	{ "question": "腐心", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "taking pains to; racking one's brains; doing everything one can" },
	{ "question": "腐敗", "answers": [ "ふはい" ], "comment": "decomposition; putrefaction; putrescence; spoilage\ncorruption; degeneracy; decay; depravity" },
	{ "question": "至る", "answers": [ "いたる" ], "comment": "to arrive at (e.g. a decision); to reach (a stage); to attain\nto lead to (a place); to get to\nto come; to arrive; to result in" },
	{ "question": "至宝", "answers": [ "しほう" ], "comment": "most valuable asset; pride of ...; most important person" },
	{ "question": "致命", "answers": [ "ちめい" ], "comment": "fatal" },
	{ "question": "興味", "answers": [ "きょうみ" ], "comment": "interest (in something); curiosity (about something); zest (for)" },
	{ "question": "舞台", "answers": [ "ぶたい" ], "comment": "stage (theatre, theater)\nscene or setting (e.g. of novel, play, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "舞扇", "answers": [ "まいおうぎ" ], "comment": "dancer's fan" },
	{ "question": "舞踊", "answers": [ "ぶよう" ], "comment": "dancing; dance" },
	{ "question": "舟", "answers": [ "ふね" ], "comment": "ship; boat; watercraft; vessel; steamship\ntank; tub; vat; trough\ncounter for boat-shaped containers (e.g. of sashimi)" },
	{ "question": "色彩", "answers": [ "しきさい" ], "comment": "colour; color; hue; tints" },
	{ "question": "芋", "answers": [ "いも" ], "comment": "tuber; taro; potato\nyokel; bumpkin" },
	{ "question": "芝", "answers": [ "しば" ], "comment": "lawn; sod; turf" },
	{ "question": "芝居", "answers": [ "しばい" ], "comment": "play; drama" },
	{ "question": "芝生", "answers": [ "しばふ" ], "comment": "lawn" },
	{ "question": "苦悩", "answers": [ "くのう" ], "comment": "suffering; distress; affliction; anguish; agony; trouble" },
	{ "question": "茂る", "answers": [ "しげる" ], "comment": "to grow thickly; to be in full leaf; to be rampant; to luxuriate; to be luxurious" },
	{ "question": "荒天", "answers": [ "こうてん" ], "comment": "stormy weather" },
	{ "question": "荒立てる", "answers": [ "あらだてる" ], "comment": "to aggravate; to make serious" },
	{ "question": "荒野", "answers": [ "こうや" ], "comment": "wasteland; wilderness; deserted land; prairie; vast plain; wilds; desert; wild land" },
	{ "question": "菓子", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "pastry; confectionery" },
	{ "question": "著者", "answers": [ "ちょしゃ" ], "comment": "author (usu. of a particular book); writer" },
	{ "question": "蓄える", "answers": [ "たくわえる" ], "comment": "to store; to save up; to stock up on; to lay in stock; to set aside\nto accumulate (e.g. knowledge); to build up (e.g. experience); to develop (e.g. one's skills)\nto grow (a beard, moustache, etc.); to wear" },
	{ "question": "薄い", "answers": [ "うすい" ], "comment": "thin\npale; light\nwatery; dilute; sparse\nweak (taste, etc.)\nslim (probability, etc.); small" },
	{ "question": "薪", "answers": [ "たきぎ" ], "comment": "firewood; kindling; fuel\npiece(s) of firewood" },
	{ "question": "薬剤師", "answers": [ "やくざいし" ], "comment": "chemist; pharmacist; apothecary" },
	{ "question": "表明", "answers": [ "ひょうめい" ], "comment": "declaration; indication; representation; manifestation; demonstration; expression; announcement; assertion" },
	{ "question": "被害", "answers": [ "ひがい" ], "comment": "(suffering) damage; injury; harm" },
	{ "question": "被災", "answers": [ "ひさい" ], "comment": "being a victim of (some disaster); suffering from" },
	{ "question": "裁判", "answers": [ "さいばん" ], "comment": "trial; judgement; judgment" },
	{ "question": "装飾", "answers": [ "そうしょく" ], "comment": "ornament; decoration" },
	{ "question": "補足", "answers": [ "ほそく" ], "comment": "supplement; complement" },
	{ "question": "製菓", "answers": [ "せいか" ], "comment": "confectionery production; baking (e.g. pastries, sweets)\nconfectionery" },
	{ "question": "襲う", "answers": [ "おそう" ], "comment": "to attack; to assail; to make an assault; to strike; to hunt down\nto succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)\nto make a sudden visit" },
	{ "question": "襲撃", "answers": [ "しゅうげき" ], "comment": "attack; charge; raid" },
	{ "question": "襲来", "answers": [ "しゅうらい" ], "comment": "invasion; raid; attack; visitation (of a calamity)" },
	{ "question": "要項", "answers": [ "ようこう" ], "comment": "important points; main points" },
	{ "question": "見込み", "answers": [ "みこみ" ], "comment": "hope; promise; possibility; chance; probability; likelihood\nexpectation; anticipation; forecast; estimate\nside of a structural member" },
	{ "question": "規則", "answers": [ "きそく" ], "comment": "rules; regulations; conventions" },
	{ "question": "規範", "answers": [ "きはん" ], "comment": "model; standard; pattern; norm; criterion; example" },
	{ "question": "解ける", "answers": [ "とける" ], "comment": "to be solved\nto loosen; to come untied\nto be removed (e.g. restrictions); to be cleared (e.g. misunderstandings); to be broken (e.g. spells, curses)\nto melt\nto come lose; to come untied; to come undone; to unravel\nto loosen up (e.g. tension)" },
	{ "question": "触れる", "answers": [ "ふれる" ], "comment": "to touch; to feel\nto experience; to come in contact with; to be emotionally moved (by); to perceive\nto touch on a subject; to allude to\nto be in conflict (with); to violate (law, copyright, etc.)\nto proclaim" },
	{ "question": "記憶", "answers": [ "きおく" ], "comment": "memory; recollection; remembrance\nstorage" },
	{ "question": "記載", "answers": [ "きさい" ], "comment": "record; statement; description; mention; listing; registration; booking; entry" },
	{ "question": "訪ねる", "answers": [ "たずねる" ], "comment": "to visit; to call on; to pay a visit to" },
	{ "question": "許す", "answers": [ "ゆるす" ], "comment": "to permit; to allow; to approve; to tolerate\nto exempt (from fine); to excuse (from); to pardon; to forgive; to release; to let off\nto confide in\nto give up; to yield" },
	{ "question": "訴える", "answers": [ "うったえる" ], "comment": "to raise; to bring to (someone's attention)\nto appeal to (reason, emotions, etc.); to work on (one's emotions); to play on (one's sympathies)\nto complain\nto sue (a person); to take someone to court\nto resort to (e.g. arms, violence)" },
	{ "question": "証拠", "answers": [ "しょうこ" ], "comment": "evidence; proof" },
	{ "question": "詰める", "answers": [ "つめる" ], "comment": "to stuff into; to jam; to cram; to pack; to fill; to plug; to stop up\nto shorten; to move closer together\nto reduce (spending); to conserve\nto focus intently on; to strain oneself to do\nto work out (details)\nto be on duty; to be stationed\nto corner (esp. an opponent's king in shogi); to trap; to checkmate\nto cut off (one's finger as an act of apology); to catch (one's finger in a door, etc.)\nto continue ...; to keep doing ... without a break\nto do ... completely; to do ... thoroughly\nto force someone into a difficult situation by ..." },
	{ "question": "詳報", "answers": [ "しょうほう" ], "comment": "full report; particulars" },
	{ "question": "詳細", "answers": [ "しょうさい" ], "comment": "detail; particulars" },
	{ "question": "誇張", "answers": [ "こちょう" ], "comment": "exaggeration" },
	{ "question": "誇示", "answers": [ "こじ" ], "comment": "ostentation; display" },
	{ "question": "認める", "answers": [ "みとめる" ], "comment": "to write up\nto recognize; to recognise; to observe; to notice\nto deem; to judge; to assess\nto approve; to deem acceptable; to allow\nto admit; to accept; to confess (to a charge)\nto watch steadily; to observe carefully\nto renown; to give renown to; to appreciate; to acknowledge" },
	{ "question": "認可", "answers": [ "にんか" ], "comment": "approval; license; licence; permission" },
	{ "question": "誤り", "answers": [ "あやまり" ], "comment": "error; mistake; slip; bug" },
	{ "question": "誤解", "answers": [ "ごかい" ], "comment": "misunderstanding" },
	{ "question": "謝る", "answers": [ "あやまる" ], "comment": "to apologize; to apologise" },
	{ "question": "警備", "answers": [ "けいび" ], "comment": "defense; defence; guard; policing; security" },
	{ "question": "警戒", "answers": [ "けいかい" ], "comment": "vigilance; caution; alertness; precaution; being on guard" },
	{ "question": "豊か", "answers": [ "ゆたか" ], "comment": "abundant; wealthy; plentiful; rich; affluent\nvery; extremely; full of; great" },
	{ "question": "豪快", "answers": [ "ごうかい" ], "comment": "hearty; exciting; stirring; lively; heroic; largehearted; splendid" },
	{ "question": "貧しい", "answers": [ "まずしい" ], "comment": "poor; needy\nlacking (quantity and quality-wise); poor; scanty; skimpy; slight; inadequate" },
	{ "question": "販路", "answers": [ "はんろ" ], "comment": "market (for goods, services, etc.); outlet (for selling); opening" },
	{ "question": "責める", "answers": [ "せめる" ], "comment": "to condemn; to blame; to criticize; to criticise; to reproach; to accuse\nto urge; to press; to pester\nto torture; to torment; to persecute\nto break in (a horse)" },
	{ "question": "賦与", "answers": [ "ふよ" ], "comment": "being endowed with (e.g. a gift); being blessed with; endowment" },
	{ "question": "贈る", "answers": [ "おくる" ], "comment": "to give (as a gift); to present\nto confer; to bestow; to award" },
	{ "question": "贈与", "answers": [ "ぞうよ" ], "comment": "donation; presentation" },
	{ "question": "贈答", "answers": [ "ぞうとう" ], "comment": "exchange of presents" },
	{ "question": "起床", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "rising; getting out of bed" },
	{ "question": "越える", "answers": [ "こえる" ], "comment": "to cross over; to cross; to pass through; to pass over (out of)\nto exceed" },
	{ "question": "越境", "answers": [ "えっきょう" ], "comment": "border transgression" },
	{ "question": "趣味", "answers": [ "しゅみ" ], "comment": "hobby; pastime\ntastes; preference; liking" },
	{ "question": "趣旨", "answers": [ "しゅし" ], "comment": "meaning; point (e.g. of a statement); gist; effect\ngoal; intent; object; aim; point" },
	{ "question": "距離", "answers": [ "きょり" ], "comment": "distance; range" },
	{ "question": "跡形", "answers": [ "あとかた" ], "comment": "trace; vestige; evidence" },
	{ "question": "跳ねる", "answers": [ "はねる" ], "comment": "to jump; to leap; to prance; to spring up; to bound; to hop\nto break up; to close; to come to an end\nto hit (e.g. to have a car hit something or someone)" },
	{ "question": "跳ぶ", "answers": [ "とぶ" ], "comment": "to fly; to soar\nto jump; to leap; to spring; to bound; to hop" },
	{ "question": "踏破", "answers": [ "とうは" ], "comment": "travelling on foot; traveling on foot\ntravelling all over" },
	{ "question": "踏襲", "answers": [ "とうしゅう" ], "comment": "following (e.g. suit, in someone's footsteps, etc.); emulation" },
	{ "question": "躍動", "answers": [ "やくどう" ], "comment": "lively motion; throb" },
	{ "question": "軒並み", "answers": [ "のきなみ" ], "comment": "row of houses; every door\ntotally; altogether; across the board" },
	{ "question": "軒先", "answers": [ "のきさき" ], "comment": "edge of the eaves; house frontage" },
	{ "question": "転倒", "answers": [ "てんとう" ], "comment": "falling down; tumbling; overturning; turning over\nreversing; inverting; inversion\ngetting upset\ncognitive distortion" },
	{ "question": "軽微", "answers": [ "けいび" ], "comment": "slight; little; insignificant" },
	{ "question": "軽薄", "answers": [ "けいはく" ], "comment": "frivolous; flippant; superficial; trifling" },
	{ "question": "載せる", "answers": [ "のせる" ], "comment": "to place on (something)\nto give (someone) a ride; to give a lift; to pick up; to help on board\nto load (luggage); to carry; to take on board\nto send out (on the airwaves, etc.)\nto deceive; to take for a ride\nto (sing) along with (musical accompaniment)\nto let (someone) take part\nto excite (someone)\nto publish (an article); to run (an ad)" },
	{ "question": "輝く", "answers": [ "かがやく" ], "comment": "to shine; to glitter; to sparkle" },
	{ "question": "輩出", "answers": [ "はいしゅつ" ], "comment": "turning out in great numbers; appearing one after the other" },
	{ "question": "農奴", "answers": [ "のうど" ], "comment": "serf" },
	{ "question": "込む", "answers": [ "こむ" ], "comment": "to be crowded; to be packed\nto be complex\nto go into; to put into; to remain (seated); to be plunged into (silence); to do thoroughly\nto do intently\nto continue in the same state" },
	{ "question": "込める", "answers": [ "こめる" ], "comment": "to load (a gun, etc.); to charge\nto put into (e.g. emotion, effort)\nto include (e.g. tax in a sales price)\nto hang over; to shroud; to enshroud; to envelop; to screen" },
	{ "question": "迎合", "answers": [ "げいごう" ], "comment": "ingratiation; going along with somebody's views; adjusting oneself (to something, to somebody); flattery\ndeuteragonist; secondary or supporting actor in a noh or kyogen play (possibly multiple actors)" },
	{ "question": "迎撃", "answers": [ "げいげき" ], "comment": "intercept; interception; counter attack" },
	{ "question": "迫真", "answers": [ "はくしん" ], "comment": "reality; true to life" },
	{ "question": "述べる", "answers": [ "のべる" ], "comment": "to state; to express; to mention" },
	{ "question": "迷子", "answers": [ "まいご" ], "comment": "lost child; lost person; stray child; missing child" },
	{ "question": "迷惑", "answers": [ "めいわく" ], "comment": "trouble; bother; annoyance" },
	{ "question": "追憶", "answers": [ "ついおく" ], "comment": "recollection; reminiscence" },
	{ "question": "退く", "answers": [ "のく" ], "comment": "to step aside; to move (i.e. out of the way); to make way\nto resign; to retire; to quit; to secede\nto step back; to move back; to retreat\nto withdraw (from the presence of a superior); to leave; to exit\nto resign; to retire; to quit\nto concede\nto move back; to draw back; to recede\nto lessen; to subside; to ebb\nto resign; to retire; to quit" },
	{ "question": "退却", "answers": [ "たいきゃく" ], "comment": "retreat; withdrawal; retirement" },
	{ "question": "退屈", "answers": [ "たいくつ" ], "comment": "tedium; boredom" },
	{ "question": "送迎", "answers": [ "そうげい" ], "comment": "seeing off and meeting on return" },
	{ "question": "逃げる", "answers": [ "にげる" ], "comment": "to escape; to run away" },
	{ "question": "逃れる", "answers": [ "のがれる" ], "comment": "to escape" },
	{ "question": "逃亡", "answers": [ "とうぼう" ], "comment": "escape; flight; running away; elopement; fleeing" },
	{ "question": "逃避", "answers": [ "とうひ" ], "comment": "escape; evasion; flight" },
	{ "question": "透写", "answers": [ "とうしゃ" ], "comment": "tracing" },
	{ "question": "透明", "answers": [ "とうめい" ], "comment": "transparent; clear" },
	{ "question": "透視", "answers": [ "とうし" ], "comment": "seeing through\nX-ray (examination)\nclairvoyance" },
	{ "question": "通勤", "answers": [ "つうきん" ], "comment": "commuting to work" },
	{ "question": "造る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct\nto prepare (food); to brew (alcohol)\nto raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train\nto till\nto draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write\nto create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose\nto coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found\nto have (a child)\nto make up (one's face, etc.)\nto fabricate (an excuse, etc.)\nto form (a line, etc.)\nto set (a record)\nto commit (a sin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "連鎖", "answers": [ "れんさ" ], "comment": "chain; chaining; catena; connection\n(genetic) linkage" },
	{ "question": "遅い", "answers": [ "おそい" ], "comment": "slow\nlate (e.g. \"late at night\")\ntoo late\ndull; stupid" },
	{ "question": "遅刻", "answers": [ "ちこく" ], "comment": "lateness; late coming" },
	{ "question": "遅咲き", "answers": [ "おそざき" ], "comment": "late blooming (flower, talent); late flowering" },
	{ "question": "遅延", "answers": [ "ちえん" ], "comment": "delay; latency" },
	{ "question": "遊戯", "answers": [ "ゆうぎ" ], "comment": "game; play; sports" },
	{ "question": "運搬", "answers": [ "うんぱん" ], "comment": "transport; transportation; conveyance; carriage" },
	{ "question": "過ごす", "answers": [ "すごす" ], "comment": "to pass (time); to spend\nto overdo (esp. of one's alcohol consumption); to drink (alcohol)\nto take care of; to support\nto overdo; to do too much\nto ... without acting on it" },
	{ "question": "過ち", "answers": [ "あやまち" ], "comment": "fault; error; indiscretion; faux pas" },
	{ "question": "過渡期", "answers": [ "かとき" ], "comment": "transition period" },
	{ "question": "道端", "answers": [ "みちばた" ], "comment": "roadside; wayside" },
	{ "question": "遠征", "answers": [ "えんせい" ], "comment": "expedition; campaign; (performer's) tour\naway series" },
	{ "question": "遣わす", "answers": [ "つかわす" ], "comment": "to send; to dispatch; to despatch\nto bestow (favour, etc.); to grant (e.g. pardon)" },
	{ "question": "遣唐使", "answers": [ "けんとうし" ], "comment": "envoy (to Tang China)" },
	{ "question": "遺産", "answers": [ "いさん" ], "comment": "inheritance; bequest; legacy; heritage" },
	{ "question": "遺跡", "answers": [ "いせき" ], "comment": "historic ruins (remains, relics); archeological site" },
	{ "question": "避暑", "answers": [ "ひしょ" ], "comment": "summering; going to a summer resort" },
	{ "question": "避暑地", "answers": [ "ひしょち" ], "comment": "summer resort" },
	{ "question": "避難", "answers": [ "ひなん" ], "comment": "taking refuge; finding shelter; evacuation; escape" },
	{ "question": "郵便", "answers": [ "ゆうびん" ], "comment": "mail service; postal service; mail; post\nmail; postal matter; postal items" },
	{ "question": "釈然", "answers": [ "しゃくぜん" ], "comment": "fully satisfied; well satisfied (e.g. with an explanation or apology); to have one's heart completely cleared of doubt or grudge" },
	{ "question": "金字塔", "answers": [ "きんじとう" ], "comment": "pyramid\nmonumental work; landmark achievement" },
	{ "question": "鈍い", "answers": [ "にぶい" ], "comment": "slow\nlate (e.g. \"late at night\")\ntoo late\ndull; stupid\ndull (e.g. a knife); blunt\nthickheaded; obtuse; stupid\ndull (sound, color, etc.); dim (light)\nslow; sluggish; inert; lethargic\nindulgent (esp. to the opposite sex); doting" },
	{ "question": "鈍感", "answers": [ "どんかん" ], "comment": "thickheaded; insensitive; dull; thick-skinned" },
	{ "question": "鈍角", "answers": [ "どんかく" ], "comment": "obtuse angle" },
	{ "question": "鉛筆", "answers": [ "えんぴつ" ], "comment": "pencil" },
	{ "question": "鋭い", "answers": [ "するどい" ], "comment": "sharp (blade); pointed\nsharp (pain); stabbing; cutting (remark); stinging; pointed (question or look); screeching (noise)\nperceptive; keen; quick (mind); astute; shrewd; discerning\nnimble; agile; quick" },
	{ "question": "鋭利", "answers": [ "えいり" ], "comment": "sharp; keen; acute" },
	{ "question": "鎖国", "answers": [ "さこく" ], "comment": "national isolation; closing the country (to foreigners)\nsakoku; policy of national isolation enacted by the Tokugawa shogunate" },
	{ "question": "鑑定", "answers": [ "かんてい" ], "comment": "judgement; judgment; expert opinion; appraisal" },
	{ "question": "鑑識", "answers": [ "かんしき" ], "comment": "judgement; judgment; discernment; discrimination; having eye for\nforensics; crime lab" },
	{ "question": "門出", "answers": [ "かどで" ], "comment": "leaving one's own house (e.g. when going to war); departure; setting out\nstarting a new life; starting life anew" },
	{ "question": "閉ざす", "answers": [ "とざす" ], "comment": "to shut; to close; to lock; to fasten\nto plunge (in grief)" },
	{ "question": "開拓", "answers": [ "かいたく" ], "comment": "reclamation (e.g. wasteland); cultivation; development\npioneering; opening up (e.g. new market); breaking new ground; trailblazing" },
	{ "question": "間違える", "answers": [ "まちがえる" ], "comment": "to make a mistake (in); to commit an error (e.g. in calculation)\nto confuse; to mistake something for something else" },
	{ "question": "闘う", "answers": [ "たたかう" ], "comment": "to make war (on); to wage war (against); to go to war (with); to fight (with); to do battle (against)\nto compete (against)\nto struggle (against adversities, etc.); to fight; to contend; to resist" },
	{ "question": "闘志", "answers": [ "とうし" ], "comment": "fighting spirit; (will to) fight" },
	{ "question": "防ぐ", "answers": [ "ふせぐ" ], "comment": "to defend against; to protect against\nto prevent; to avert; to avoid" },
	{ "question": "防御", "answers": [ "ぼうぎょ" ], "comment": "defense; defence; safeguard; protection" },
	{ "question": "降りる", "answers": [ "おりる" ], "comment": "to descend (e.g. a mountain); to go down; to come down\nto alight (e.g. from bus); to get off; to disembark; to dismount\nto step down; to retire; to give up; to quit\nto be granted; to be issued; to be given\nto form (of frost, dew, mist, etc.)\nto be passed (from the body; e.g. of a roundworm)" },
	{ "question": "限り", "answers": [ "かぎり" ], "comment": "limit; limits; bounds\ndegree; extent; scope\nas far as possible; as much as possible; to the best of one's ability; very much\nunless (after neg. verb)\nthe end; the last\nas long as; only\nend; finish; stop\nbounds; limits\ndelivery date (of a futures contract)\nfinale (of a noh song); end of an act (in joruri or kabuki); final performance of the day (in vaudeville)\ncounter for slices (esp. thick slices); counter for cuts (e.g. fish, meat)\nonly; just\nsince; after\nremaining (in a particular state)" },
	{ "question": "陣営", "answers": [ "じんえい" ], "comment": "camp (group of same ideological beliefs); faction (of political party)\nmilitary camp; encampment; cantonment" },
	{ "question": "陣頭", "answers": [ "じんとう" ], "comment": "head of an army" },
	{ "question": "陰影", "answers": [ "いんえい" ], "comment": "shadow; shade; shading; gloom\nnuance; shades of meaning; subtleties" },
	{ "question": "険しい", "answers": [ "けわしい" ], "comment": "precipitous; rugged; inaccessible; impregnable; steep\ngrim; severe; stern" },
	{ "question": "隠居", "answers": [ "いんきょ" ], "comment": "retirement\nretired person" },
	{ "question": "隠然", "answers": [ "いんぜん" ], "comment": "latent; hidden; secret; behind the scenes" },
	{ "question": "隣", "answers": [ "となり" ], "comment": "neighbor (neighbour); next to (esp. living next door to)" },
	{ "question": "隣人", "answers": [ "りんじん" ], "comment": "neighbour; neighbor; neighbourhood; neighborhood" },
	{ "question": "隷属", "answers": [ "れいぞく" ], "comment": "subordination; servitude; servility; vassalage; slavery\nsubordinate; underling" },
	{ "question": "雄大", "answers": [ "ゆうだい" ], "comment": "grand; magnificent; majestic; great; sublime" },
	{ "question": "雌", "answers": [ "めす" ], "comment": "female (animal)\nfemale; woman\nwife" },
	{ "question": "雌雄", "answers": [ "しゆう" ], "comment": "male and female (animals); the two sexes\nvictory and defeat; strengths and weaknesses" },
	{ "question": "雑煮", "answers": [ "ぞうに" ], "comment": "soup containing rice cakes and vegetables (New Year's dish)" },
	{ "question": "雑踏", "answers": [ "ざっとう" ], "comment": "hustle and bustle; throng; crowd; congestion; traffic jam" },
	{ "question": "離合", "answers": [ "りごう" ], "comment": "alliance and rupture; meeting and parting" },
	{ "question": "難儀", "answers": [ "なんぎ" ], "comment": "affliction; hardship; difficulty; suffering" },
	{ "question": "雷鳴", "answers": [ "らいめい" ], "comment": "thunder" },
	{ "question": "需要", "answers": [ "じゅよう" ], "comment": "demand; request" },
	{ "question": "震動", "answers": [ "しんどう" ], "comment": "shock; tremor; impact; vibration" },
	{ "question": "霧笛", "answers": [ "むてき" ], "comment": "foghorn" },
	{ "question": "露骨", "answers": [ "ろこつ" ], "comment": "frank; blunt; plain; outspoken\nconspicuous; open\nbroad; suggestive; lewd" },
	{ "question": "静寂", "answers": [ "せいじゃく" ], "comment": "silence; stillness; quietness" },
	{ "question": "非凡", "answers": [ "ひぼん" ], "comment": "prodigy; rare; unique; extraordinary" },
	{ "question": "革", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "leather\nleather; tanned animal hide\nkanji \"leather\" radical (radical 177)" },
	{ "question": "音響", "answers": [ "おんきょう" ], "comment": "sound; noise; echo; acoustics; audio" },
	{ "question": "頂く", "answers": [ "いただく" ], "comment": "to receive; to get; to accept; to take; to buy\nto eat; to drink\nto be crowned with; to wear (on one's head); to have (on top)\nto have (as one's leader); to live under (a ruler); to install (a president)\nto get somebody to do something" },
	{ "question": "預ける", "answers": [ "あずける" ], "comment": "to give into custody; to leave (a child) in the care of; to entrust; to deposit\nto lean on; to put one's weight on" },
	{ "question": "頭髪", "answers": [ "とうはつ" ], "comment": "hair (of head)" },
	{ "question": "頼む", "answers": [ "たのむ" ], "comment": "to request; to beg; to ask\nto call; to order; to reserve\nto entrust to\nto rely on" },
	{ "question": "風雅", "answers": [ "ふうが" ], "comment": "elegance; grace; refinement; good taste" },
	{ "question": "首尾", "answers": [ "しゅび" ], "comment": "beginning and end; from beginning to end\nresult; outcome; course of events\ndealing with something successfully" },
	{ "question": "香料", "answers": [ "こうりょう" ], "comment": "flavoring; flavouring; spices\nfragrance; perfume; incense\ncondolence gift" },
	{ "question": "香水", "answers": [ "こうすい" ], "comment": "perfume\nscented water used for purification; water offering to Buddha" },
	{ "question": "馬匹", "answers": [ "ばひつ" ], "comment": "horses" },
	{ "question": "駆け", "answers": [ "かけ" ], "comment": "canter; gallop" },
	{ "question": "駆使", "answers": [ "くし" ], "comment": "free use\nto use freely; to make free use of; to have good command (e.g. of a language)\nto drive someone on" },
	{ "question": "驚く", "answers": [ "おどろく" ], "comment": "to be surprised; to be astonished" },
	{ "question": "驚嘆", "answers": [ "きょうたん" ], "comment": "wonder; admiration; being struck with admiration" },
	{ "question": "骨", "answers": [ "ほね" ], "comment": "knack; skill; trick; secret; know-how; the ropes; hang\nbone\nframe\noutline; core\nbackbone; spirit; fortitude\nlaborious; troublesome; difficult" },
	{ "question": "高僧", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "high priest; virtuous priest" },
	{ "question": "高齢", "answers": [ "こうれい" ], "comment": "advanced (old) age" },
	{ "question": "鬼", "answers": [ "おに" ], "comment": "oni; ogre; demon\nspirit of a deceased person\nogre-like person (i.e. fierce, relentless, merciless, etc.)\nit (in a game of tag, hide-and-seek, etc.)\nChinese \"ghost\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\nvery; extremely; super-" },
	{ "question": "魚拓", "answers": [ "ぎょたく" ], "comment": "fish print" },
	{ "question": "魚網", "answers": [ "ぎょもう" ], "comment": "fishing net" },
	{ "question": "鮮やか", "answers": [ "あざやか" ], "comment": "vivid; bright; brilliant; clear; fresh; vibrant\nskillful; skilful; adept; adroit; deft; brilliant; beautiful; fine; excellent" },
	{ "question": "鮮明", "answers": [ "せんめい" ], "comment": "vivid; clear; distinct" },
	{ "question": "麗姿", "answers": [ "れいし" ], "comment": "beautiful figure" },
	{ "question": "麗筆", "answers": [ "れいひつ" ], "comment": "beautiful brushwork or writing" },
	{ "question": "黙読", "answers": [ "もくどく" ], "comment": "reading silently" },
	{ "question": "鼓吹", "answers": [ "こすい" ], "comment": "inspiration; advocacy; encouragement" },
	{ "question": "鼓笛隊", "answers": [ "こてきたい" ], "comment": "drum and fife band" }
]
}
